Select Page

Privacy Statement

### NEW PRIVACY AND DATA SECURITY STATEMENT

This Privacy Statement was amended as of February 20th 2024 and is effective as of that date.

Thank you for visiting Slashdot Media's Online and Mobile Resources (defined below), and for viewing this Privacy Statement. This Privacy Statement applies to any online and mobile resource that links to this Statement, including SlashdotMedia.com, SourceForge.net, and Slashdot.org, Our full Privacy Statement, contained in the pages that follow, serves to give notice to data subjects, other than our _Workforce and Job Applicants_ (defined below), about the types of Personal Data (defined below) we collect as a controller, how we use it, who we disclose it with and why, your rights with respect to your Personal Data, and what we do to try to protect it. In addition, the [Cross-Border Data Transfer](#CrossBorderData) section addresses certain Personal Data we receive from our business customers to process in connections with providing them services that is imported to the United States from certain European territories. We encourage you to read our full Statement carefully. _Workforce and Job Applicants_ can obtain a copy of a notice of the data practices that apply to them by contacting us [here.](#PrivacyOffice) This Statement also outlines privacy rights and options that you may have, and how to exercise them, including for our Workforce and Job Applicants, as more fully set forth in [Your U.S. State Privacy Rights](#CCPA), [Your GDPR Privacy Rights](#exercisingYourRights) and our [DPF Policy](https://slashdotmedia.com/dpf-policy/) . Click here for a table of contents that allows you to link to specific sections.

### SOME IMPORTANT VOCABULARY

Although not itself a contract, this Privacy Statement is an important document that explains how we address some of our legal obligations, and your related legal rights, involving Personal Data. Clarity is, therefore, important. We will use this section to let you know about some words that have special meanings whenever you see them in this Statement.

Let's start with the word **"Statement"** itself: when we reference **"this Statement"**, **"this Privacy Statement"** and **"our Statement"**, we mean the Privacy Statement you are reading now. Wherever we say **"Company"**, **"we"**, **"us"**, **"our"**, or **"SDM"**, we mean Slashdot Media LLC or its affiliates, as applicable.

When we talk about our **"Online and Mobile Resources"**, we mean all websites, portals, or other features SDM operates, that link to this Statement. SDM also offers certain business-to-business marketing and advertising services. When we refer to **"Lead Ads and Content"** we mean the special types of advertisements and other content, such as whitepapers and email contents, containing forms or other means for users to provide information showing their interest in the applicable product or service. The term **"Affinity Action"** means when you "follow" us, "like" us or take a similar or analogous action on our external social media presence.

Finally, and perhaps most importantly, when we refer to **"Personal Data"** we mean information that identifies or can be used to reasonably identify you, or that is otherwise treated as personal information or Personal Data under applicable laws (for example, IP address, cookie IDs, device IDs). Where information does not qualify as Personal Data under applicable law (e.g., information that has been anonymized, or aggregated), we will not treat it as such.

### WHO DOES THIS STATEMENT APPLY TO?

This Statement describes our Personal Data practices regarding the following groups of data subjects:

* individuals that visit, use, access, or interact with our Online and Mobile Resources and/or Lead Ads and Content (**"Visitors and Users"**);
* contact persons and representatives of customers of our advertising, marketing and lead generation services (**"Customer Personnel"**); and
* contact persons and representatives of our third-party vendors and business partners (**"Vendor and Business Partner Personnel"**).

The categories of data we collect from each of these groups, and the ways in which we use it, differs.

While our data practices regarding our current and former personnel and job applicants (**"Workforce and Job Applicants"**) are described in a separate notice and not this Statement, this Statement does explain how those data subjects can exercise their privacy rights under applicable law. With the exception of our [DPF Policy](https://slashdotmedia.com/dpf-policy/) and the [Cross-Border Data Transfer](#CrossBorderData) section, this Statement does not include Personal Data we do not control but may process for our business customers to provide them services.

#### Our Visitors and Users

This Privacy Statement applies to Visitors and Users of our Online and Mobile Resources and those that interact with our lead generation ads and content including content we may send as part of email campaigns.

#### Our Customers and Customer Personnel

Our business customers enter into contracts with us. That contract is separate from this Statement and has its own terms and conditions for processing of Personal Data on their behalf and governing our overall confidentiality, data privacy and data security obligations. As a result, those terms, and not this Statement, apply to the Personal Data of business customers that we process for them. However, we independently collect and process for ourselves Personal Data of Customer Personnel, and this Statement covers that. In addition, our [DPF Policy](https://slashdotmedia.com/dpf-policy/) and the [Cross-Border Data Transfer](#CrossBorderData) section covers certain Personal Data of our business customers that we import to the U.S. to process in connection with providing them services.

#### Our Workforce and Job Applicants

We collect and retain the types of professional or employment related Personal Data you would expect an employer to have about its workforce and job applicants, however, rather than describe those practices in this Statement, we provide legally required notices of collection and describe our use and sharing of the Personal Data of our Workforce and Applicants in greater detail in a separate notice. Contact us [here](#PrivacyOffice) for more information. However, this Statement does explain how our Workforce and Job Applicants may exercise their privacy rights under applicable law.

#### Our Vendors and Business Partners

Like all corporate enterprises, we buy goods and services, lease equipment and office space and attend industry events. In doing so, we interact with personnel of existing and potential Vendors from whom we necessarily collect certain Personal Data. We describe our use of Vendor and Business Partner Personnel Personal Data that we control generally in this Statement; provided, however, that our confidential contracts with those parties may address other Personal Data processing relating to those parties.

### WHAT PERSONAL DATA DO WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU AND HOW DO WE USE IT?

We collect the Personal Data we control in three ways: (i) Personal Data you voluntarily provide to us; (ii) Personal Data we collect through automated/technical means; and (iii) Personal Data that we collect from publicly available sources or obtain from third parties. We may also infer other Personal Data from the Personal Data that we collect and control. We describe our Personal Data processing practices regarding each of those collection methods in the tables below. Additional detail is provided in the [Comprehensive Privacy Laws](#ComprehensiveLaws) section that provide required notices to residents of certain U.S. states and for the UK, European Economic Area and Switzerland.

**_By using our Online and Mobile Resources, you are signifying to us that you have read and understand this Privacy Statement._**

We provide more detailed descriptions of our Personal Data practices by source in the charts below. However, regardless of source, SMD may use your Personal Data for any purposes not inconsistent with our statements under this Privacy Statement, or otherwise made by us in writing at the point of collection, and not prohibited by applicable law, including, without limitation, to:

* allow you to participate in the features we offer on our Online and Mobile Resources;
* facilitate, manage, personalize, and improve your user experience;
* process your registration, manage your account, and/or upload your user generated content;
* transact with you, provide services or information you request, respond to your comments, questions and requests, serve you content and/or advertising, and send you notices;
* market to you and other promotional purposes;
* sell to our business customers, subject to limitations, as more fully explained [here;](#rightsToKnow)
* improve our products and service and for other internal business purposes;
* tailor our content, advertisements, and offers;
* fulfill other purposes disclosed at the time you provide your Personal Data or otherwise where we are legally permitted or required to do so;
* determine your location and manage digital content (e.g., territory restrictions or customization); and
* prevent and address fraud, breach of policies or terms, and threats of harm, enforce rights and/or comply with law and legal process.

Without limiting the generality of the forgoing, please see the following sections below regarding distinctions between Voluntarily Submitted Data, Automatically Collected Data, and Data Collected from Other Sources.

#### Voluntarily Submitted Data

If you choose to participate in or make use of certain activities and features available via our Online and Mobile Resources, you will need to provide us with data about yourself. The types of Personal Data you will be submitting to us in those situations is almost always limited to basic identifiers such as your name, email address, mailing address, and phone number. Below are some of the ways you voluntarily give us your Personal Data and information on how and why we use it:

| ### Data we collect voluntarily provided by you when you register on our site, create or claim a free or paid listing, connect with Slashdot Media sales representatives, fill out a form, write a review, write a comment, interact with website tools, upload images or content, e-mail us or subscribe to one of our email lists. This data is directly provided by you. |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Categories of Personal Data we collect voluntarily from you include:** | * If you register as a user, we collect Personal Data such as your full name, business or personal email address, job title, the name of your company, industry sector, the state/county in which you are based, business email address, your telephone number, and job title;<br>* You may provide Personal Data when writing a review, submitting a forum or blog post, submitting a comment, submitting a support or bug ticket, editing a wiki, uploading files or images, open-source code, or inbound emailing to an open-source project list;<br>* Your company website URL;<br>* What you are interested in hearing about (e.g., lead generation or website review);<br>* What advertising channels you use such as pay per click, pay per view, fixed, or other advertising channels;<br>* Data about the software you offer (e.g., the product name, type of software, and product description);<br>* Data we require so we may invoice you, including your payment details and billing data; and<br>* You may also provide Personal Data when you communicate with us including your full name, contact details and business email address, phone number and details of any such communications. |
| **We use this Personal Data in connection with our business, including:** | * Fulfilling your requests, for example, to publish your listing and other submitted content, to provide you with details of leads (including their name, data about their business, software requirements and follow up next steps (e.g., request a demo)), and to invoice you appropriately;<br>* Managing your profile and listings;<br>* Providing consultation services;<br>* Verifying the validity of your review(s) and blocking false, misleading, malicious, obscene, or otherwise objectionable content;<br>* Sending you email including, but not limited to service announcements, account related messages, project related updates, and subscribed newsletters;<br>* Sending marketing information and offers to business contacts regarding Slashdot Media services;<br>* Notifying you about special offers available from us, our affiliates or partners, which may be of interest to you;<br>* Inviting you to provide reviews about other products and services, and to consider other services provided by SMD;<br>* Providing our services, managing our Online and Mobile Resources, responding to your questions, investigating any complaints, and providing customer service;<br>* Administering our services and Online and Mobile Resources, investigating complaints, and providing customer service;<br>* Customizing your digital experience;<br>* Responding to your questions and requests and otherwise customizing your digital experience;<br>* Resolving disputes;<br>* For internal analysis and research purposes to help us to measure interest in and improve our services;<br>* In connection with leads and ads, and subject to applicable law, to disclose it with our customers and Third-Party Digital Businesses for their own marketing purposes;<br>* Preventing prohibited or illegal activities or harm to us or others;<br>* Enforcing our policies or terms;<br>* To otherwise operate our business subject to the limitation of applicable law; and<br>* As required by law or legal process. |
| **We use this Personal Data because:** | * It is necessary to comply with applicable laws or regulations; and/or<br>* To operate our business, including to:<br>* * Manage and promote our business and brand;<br>    * Provide and improve our services;<br>    * Operate our business;<br>    * Improve the performance and user experience of our Online and Mobile Resources;<br>    * Monitor, investigate and report any attempts to breach the security of our Online and Mobile Resources; and<br>    * Resolve any concerns or disputes you may have. |

#### Automatically Collected Data

When you visit or use our Online and Mobile Resources, basic data about your internet/electronic activity is automatically collected through your browser via tracking technologies, such as “cookies.” Cookies are small text files downloaded onto your computer or mobile device. Cookies allow us to collect your IP address and other usage data, recognize your computer or mobile device, and store some data about your preferences for using our Online and Mobile Resources or past actions, such as described in the table below:

| ### Data we collect about your use of our Online and Mobile Resources(Automatically Collected). |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Categories of Personal Data we collect automatically about you include:** | * Data recorded in our logs, including URL, IP address, browser and OS data, timestamp, referring site, geolocation, and other standard browser data;<br>* Behavioral data (such as data on the behavior or presumed interests of individuals which are linked to those individuals and may be used to create a user profile) pages viewed, images viewed, documents downloaded and links to other sites followed; and<br>* Data captured by our cookies (see our [Cookie Policy](https://slashdotmedia.com/opt-out-choices/)). |
| **We use this Personal Data in connection with our business, including:** | * To personalize your experience on our Online and Mobile Resources;<br>* Operating our Online and Mobile Resources, and developing and improving our products and services;<br>* Analytical, statistical, and trend analysis to improve the user experience and performance of our Online and Mobile Resources;<br>* To facilitate your access to and use of our Online and Mobile Resources;<br>* In connection with leads and ads, and subject to applicable law, to disclose it with our customers and Third-Party Digital Businesses for their own marketing purposes;<br>* Resolving disputes and troubleshooting problems;<br>* To otherwise operate our business subject to the limitations of applicable law; and<br>* As required by law or legal process. |
| **We use this Personal Data because:** | * It is necessary to comply with applicable laws or regulations; and/or<br>* We use it to operate our business, including to:<br>* * Monitor, investigate, and report any attempts to breach the security of our Online and Mobile Resources;<br>    * Improve the performance and user experience of our Online and Mobile Resources;<br>    * Develop our product and service offerings for service users and our customers;<br>    * You consented (where required under applicable law) to the use of your data for marketing. Where we rely on your consent, you have the right to withdraw this consent by contacting us via the information below or unsubscribing via the opt-out functionality provided in our marketing communications to you; and<br>    * Resolve any concerns or disputes you may have. |

#### Data Collected from Other Sources

We collect Personal Data from publicly available sources and from third parties (such as data brokers), which we may combine with Personal Data you have provided to us or that we have collected automatically.

| ### Data that we collect from other sources |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Categories of Personal Data we collect about you include:** | * Contact data, such as name, email address, mailing address, and phone number, as well as, potentially, workplace and job title for contact persons at prospective customers;<br>* Uniquely identifiable mobile device data;<br>* Geolocation data;<br>* Data collected by third-party tracking technologies, including:<br>* * URL, IP address, browser and OS data, timestamp, referring site, and other standard browser data;<br>    * Behavioral data (such as data on the behavior or presumed interests of individuals which are linked to those individuals and may be used to create a user profile) pages viewed, images viewed, documents downloaded, and links to other sites followed; and<br>    * Behavioral data from interactions with third-party social media sites and applications.<br>* Data collected from third-party mail services (as described below). |
| **We use this Personal Data in connection with our business, including:** | * Identifying prospective customers;<br>* Managing customer relationships;<br>* Managing your profile and listings;<br>* Sending you service emails (e.g., service announcements and messages relating to your account);<br>* Providing consultation services;<br>* Notifying you about special offers available from us and our affiliates or partners, which may be of interest to you;<br>* Sending marketing to business contacts regarding our services and products which may be of interest and to promote our business and brand;<br>* In connection with leads and ads, and subject to applicable law, to disclose it with our customers and Third-Party Digital Businesses for their own marketing purposes;<br>* Administering our services and Online and Mobile Resources;<br>* Responding to your questions and requests and otherwise customizing your digital experience;<br>* For internal analysis and research to help us to measure interest in and improve our services;<br>* Preventing prohibited or illegal activities;<br>* Enforcing our policies or terms;<br>* To otherwise operate our business subject to the limitation of applicable law; and<br>* As required by law or legal process. |
| **We use this Personal Data because:** | * It is necessary to comply with applicable laws or regulations;<br>* We have a legitimate business interest to:<br>* * Manage and promote our business and brand;<br>    * Provide and improve our services;<br>    * Operate our business;<br>    * Obtain payment for our services;<br>    * Improve the performance and user experience of our Online and Mobile Resources;<br>    * Monitor, investigate, and report any attempts to breach the security of our Online and Mobile Resources; and<br>    * Resolve any concerns or disputes you may have.<br>* You consented (where required under applicable law) to the use of your data for marketing. Where we rely upon your consent, you have the right to withdraw this consent by contacting the Data Protection Officer via the contact details above or unsubscribing via the opt-out functionality provided in our marketing communications to you. |

Additional data about cookies and tracking technologies is available [here](https://www.ftc.gov/policy-notices/privacy-policy/internet-cookies).

If you access our Online and Mobile Resources from a phone or other mobile device, the mobile provider may transmit certain data to us such as uniquely identifiable mobile device data. That, in turn, allows us to collect mobile phone numbers and associate them with the mobile device identification data. You can control some of the information disclosed with us through your device settings.

When you use our Online and Mobile Resources, we may allow third party providers (**"Third-Party Digital Businesses"**) to place their own cookies or similar technologies to engage in the same types of collection we describe above.

As part of our services, we will sometimes initially identify prospective customers via public websites or applications operated by third parties such as [Seamless.ai](https://seamless.ai/) . The type of data we collect is the same as that described above, such as name, email address, mailing address, and phone number, as well as potentially workplace and job title of the contact persons at those prospective customers. We also purchase data sets from third parties and use them to check the accuracy of the data we collected from such public sources. In some cases, we may use the data we purchased from a third party even if we did not previously collect it from a public source. We exercise reasonable care and due diligence in purchasing data from third parties and only do so when we are able to obtain assurances that they obtained Personal Data in a lawful manner.

#### User Beware: External Sites, Apps, Links, and Social Media

We maintain a presence on one or more external social media platforms such as X, Facebook, Instagram, and LinkedIn. We may further allow the community features of our Online and Mobile Resources to connect with, or be viewable from, that external social media presence. Similarly, our Online and Mobile Resources may contain links to other websites or apps controlled by third parties.

If you interact with our Online and Mobile Resources using plug-ins for any social networks, including Facebook, X, or YouTube, your activity may be available for review by those network operators and other users of such social networks.

We and the third-party owning such social network plug-ins process the Personal Data collected from the interaction with such plug-ins as joint controllers. The processing operations that we carry out on a joint controller basis are the collection and communication by transmission to the relevant network operator of Personal Data related to our visitors. Where these third parties carry out further processing operations for their own purposes, they will be considered as the sole data controllers. Where you access our resources from the EEA, UK, or Switzerland, our joint controller agreements with such third parties will apply. These agreements determine the respective responsibilities for compliance with the obligations under the GDPR and equivalent regulations with regard to the joint processing, as specified in the applicable product terms of Facebook, X, and YouTube. Please note that the information collected by means of social network plug-ins used may entail the transfer of your Personal Data by the corresponding third parties to countries outside the European Economic Area. These international transfers of data are controlled in their entirety by the relevant third party as set out in their respective privacy and cookie policies and will generally rely on these social networks being DPF certified.

We are not responsible for the content on, or the privacy practices of, social media platforms, or any third-party sites or apps to which we link. Those apps, sites and platforms are not controlled by us and therefore have their own privacy policies and terms of use. **To be clear: neither this Statement nor the terms of use appearing on or in any of our Online and Mobile Resources apply to our social media presence or any third-party sites or apps to which we may link.** That means even if you take an Affinity Action on our specific social media profile, and identifiers about you are automatically collected and given to us as a result, that collection and transfer is governed by the privacy policies and other terms of the applicable social media platform. If you have questions about how those apps, sites and platforms collect, use and disclose Personal Data, you should carefully read their privacy policies and contact them using the contact information they provide.

### HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR PERSONAL DATA?

We retain your Personal Data for a period of time consistent with the purpose of collection and processing, fulfilling our legal obligations and enforcing our agreements and defending our legitimate interests. The retention period for Personal Data is determined by us based on the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the Personal Data being processed, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of the Personal Data, whether we can achieve the purposes of the processing through other means, and any applicable legal requirements. For example, we will retain certain identifiers for as long as it is necessary to continue maintaining your account and providing you our products and services, to comply with our tax, accounting, and recordkeeping obligations, and for research, development, and safety purposes, as well as an additional period as necessary to protect, defend, or establish our rights, defend against potential claims, and to comply with our legal obligations.

### WHEN AND TO WHOM DO WE DISCLOSE PERSONAL DATA?

We may disclose your Personal Data as described below, subject to the requirements of the Comprehensive Privacy Laws, such as lawful basis for processing under EU/UK/Swiss laws and opt out under U.S. Privacy Laws.

#### Affiliates

Subject to applicable law, we may disclose Personal Data to other corporate affiliates who will use such data in the same way as we can under this Statement.

#### Legal Requirements

We may disclose Personal Data to government authorities, and to other third parties, as required or permitted by law, including responding to court orders and subpoenas.

#### To Prevent Harm

We also may disclose Personal Data when we have reason to believe that someone is causing injury to or interference with our rights or property or harming or potentially harming other persons or property.

#### Business Transactions

If we, or any of our affiliates, sell or transfer all or substantially all of our assets, equity interests or securities, or are acquired by one or more third parties as a result of an acquisition, merger, sale, reorganization, divestiture, consolidation, or liquidation, Personal Data may be one of the transferred assets. Such disclosures may include pre-transaction disclosures such as during due diligence.

#### Vendors and Business Partners

We also disclose Personal Data to service providers, contractors, or processors, and business partners (our **"Vendors"**) who need it to perform services for us under the contracts we have with them, including Third Party Digital Businesses (e.g., operators of cookies and tracking technologies associated with our Online and Mobile Resources).

#### Customers

As a data-driven business-to-business demand generation marketing and technology company, we provide services to help our business customers understand and expand their audiences such as email marketing, lead generation and advertising. As part of those services, we collect certain Personal Data that is then sold as part of our broader service offerings. In almost all cases, only a name, email address, work title and location, and a phone number will be sold. **You can withdraw consent, or otherwise instruct us not to sell, or further sell, your Personal Data at any time by visiting our opt-out/do not sell portal found [here](https://privacyportal-cdn.onetrust.com/dsarwebform/611e70e2-1994-43ff-b07b-646df870db4b/c1c0acac-ab24-4dac-b3e6-43421a684626.html).**

### HOW DO WE PROTECT COLLECTED PERSONAL DATA?

#### Our Data Security Program

We have adopted, implemented, and maintain an enterprise-wide corporate data security and privacy program that includes technical, organizational, administrative, and other security measures designed to protect, as required by applicable law, against reasonably anticipated or actual threats to the security of your Personal Data (the **"Security Program"**). We have reason to believe our Security Program is reasonable and appropriate for our business and the nature of foreseeable risks to the Personal Data we collect and process. Nonetheless, we cannot guarantee that your Personal Data, whether during transmission or while stored on our systems, otherwise in our care, or the care of our Vendors, will be free from unauthorized access or that loss or accidental destruction will never occur. Except for our duty under applicable law to maintain the Security Program, we disclaim, to the maximum extent the law allows, any liability for any theft or loss of, unauthorized access or damage to, or interception of any data or communications including Personal Data.

### YOUR GENERAL RIGHTS AND OPTIONS

If we are using your Personal Data to send you marketing materials, such as newsletters or product alerts via email, you may opt out / withdraw your consent by following the instructions linked or otherwise provided in the applicable email or other communication. In addition, residents of certain jurisdictions have additional rights as set forth in the [U.S. State Privacy Rights](#rightsToKnow) and [GDPR Privacy Rights](#exercisingYourRights) sections below. When we receive your request, we will take reasonable steps to remove your name from our distribution lists, but it may take time to do so. You may still receive materials for a period of time after you opt out. Opting out of or changing Affinity Actions or other submissions or requests made on our external social media presence, may require that you do so directly on that applicable platform as we do not control their procedures.

Some information about your use of our Online and Mobile Resources and certain third-party services may be collected using tracking technologies across time and services and used by SMD and third parties for purposes such as to associate different devices you use, and deliver relevant and retargeted ads and/or other content to you on the Service and certain third-party services. Some browsers have a do not track (“DNT”) feature that lets you tell websites that you do not want to have your online activities tracked. We do not support DNT because there is no industry consensus on how they should be treated. We do, however, support Global Privacy Control (“GPC”) in jurisdictions that require it, such as California. The GPC signal communicates a Do Not Sell / Share / Target request from a global privacy control if enabled for that browser or device, or the data subject, if they can be identified. For more information regarding GPC, see the U.S. Privacy Laws section below.

You also have additional rights under certain laws to withdraw consent, limit processing, and/or to instruct us not to sell / share your Personal Data or use it for targeted advertising. We describe those rights and the procedure for exercising them [here](#ComprehensiveLaws).

### CHILDREN'S PRIVACY

U.S. Federal law imposes special restrictions and obligations on commercial website operators who direct their operations toward and collect and use Personal Data from children under the age of 13. Certain Comprehensive Privacy Laws also regulate Personal Data processing practices involving children and other minors. We take those age-related requirements very seriously, and, consistent with them, do not intend for our Online and Mobile Resources to be used by persons under the age of majority, and do not intend to otherwise collect Personal Data from or about minors. Moreover, we do not otherwise knowingly collect Personal Data from minors. If we become aware that anyone under the age of majority has submitted Personal Data to us, we will delete that data other than to retain records of that action. If you are a parent or legal guardian and believe we have collected Personal Data about your minor child, you can contact us [here](#PrivacyOffice). California minors have certain rights in addition to those discussed in this section. Click [here](#CaliforniaMinors) for more information for California minors.

### COMPREHENSIVE PRIVACY LAWS

Privacy and data protection laws vary around the world and among the individual United States. Our obligations arising under the majority of the world’s privacy laws, including U.S. federal and most state laws, are identified by risk assessments that we conduct to ensure we act reasonably and responsibly when processing your Personal Data. In some jurisdictions, however, privacy laws grant you, the data subject, certain specific rights regarding your Personal Data. We refer to these types of privacy laws as **"Comprehensive Privacy Laws."** Examples of Comprehensive Privacy Laws include the European Union (**"EU GDPR"**), and United Kingdom's variant of the General Data Protection Regulation (**"UK GDPR"**) and Switzerland's data protection law based on GDPR (collectively, the **"GDPR"**), and the consumer privacy statutes of several U.S. states, such as California, Colorado, Utah, Virginia, and effective July 1, 2024, Texas (**"U.S. Privacy Laws"**). In other jurisdictions, such as Nevada, more narrow privacy laws have some features of Comprehensive Privacy Laws such as the right to opt-out of the sale of your Personal Data.

The nature and locations of our business activities make us subject to some, though not necessarily all, Comprehensive Privacy Laws. We are for instance, subject to the California Consumer Privacy Act, or **"CCPA"** and the GDPR, and effective July 1, 2024, the Texas Data Privacy and Security Act (**"TDPSA"**). As such, when we collect Personal Data from data subjects protected by the CCPA, TDPSA (once effective), or GDPR, we become subject to, and those data subjects have rights under, those Comprehensive Privacy Laws. This section of our Statement is used to explain your rights under those laws. For purposes of this section, the words **"you** and **"your** mean only California and Texas consumers (as defined by CCPA and TDPSA) and data subjects whose Personal Data was collected while they were in a GDPR jurisdiction.

Questions about how the Comprehensive Privacy Laws of other jurisdictions might apply to us can be directed to us through the contact data found [here](#SDM).

### YOUR RIGHTS AND OUR OBLIGATIONS UNDER U.S. PRIVACY LAWS

#### Categories of Data Collected

We collected and processed the following categories of Personal Data within the 12 months prior to the effective date of this Privacy Statement:

* **identifiers** such as name, address, email address, IP address, and other similar identifiers
* * **Recipients:** Service Providers (e.g., general IT, cloud computing, software, and other business vendors, data analytics providers, data processors, payment processors, and marketing companies), other members of our corporate group, and/or other parties (e.g., litigants and government entities).
    * **Sale/Share:** Third-Party Digital Businesses and our business customers.
* **Personal Data under the Customer Records provision of the California Civil Code** such as a name, address, telephone number, credit card number
* * **Recipients:** Service Providers (e.g., general IT, cloud computing, software, and other business vendors, data processors, and payment processors), other members of our corporate group, and/or other parties (e.g., litigants and government entities).
    * **Sale/Share:** Third-Party Digital Businesses and our business customers.
* **Commercial data** such as products or services purchased or considered
* * **Recipients:** Service Providers (e.g., general IT, cloud computing, software, and other business vendors, data analytics providers, data processors, and marketing companies), other members of our corporate group, and/or other parties (e.g., litigants and government entities).
    * **Sale/Share:** Third-Party Digital Businesses and our business customers.
* **Internet/electronic activity** such as browsing history and search history
* * **Recipients:** Service Providers (e.g., general IT, cloud computing, software, and other business vendors, data analytics providers, data processors, and marketing companies), other members of our corporate group, and/or other parties (e.g., litigants and government entities).
    * **Sale/Share:** Third-Party Digital Businesses and our business customers.
* **Geolocation data** including geographic coordinates/physical location
* * **Recipients:** Service Providers (e.g., general IT, cloud computing, software, and other business vendors, data analytics providers, data processors, and marketing companies), other members of our corporate group, and/or other parties (e.g., litigants and government entities).
    * **Sale/Share:** Third-Party Digital Businesses and our business customers.
* **Audio, video, electronic** or other similar data
* * **Recipients:** Service Providers (e.g., general IT, cloud computing, software, and other business vendors, premises security vendors, and call center providers), other members of our corporate group, and/or other parties (e.g., litigants and government entities).
    * **Sale/Share:** N/A.
* **Professional or employment related data** such as job title and company
* * **Recipients:** Service Providers (e.g., general IT, cloud computing, software, and other business vendors, and data processors), other members of our corporate group, and/or other parties (e.g., litigants and government entities).
    * **Sale/Share:** Our business customers.
* **Inferences drawn from the foregoing** to create a profile about a consumer reflecting the an individual's commercial preferences, predispositions, behavior, and attitudes.
* * **Recipients:** Service Providers (e.g., general IT, cloud computing, software, and other business vendors, data analytics providers, data processors, and marketing companies), other members of our corporate group, and/or other parties (e.g., litigants and government entities).
    * **Sale/Share:** Third-Party Digital Businesses and our business customers.
* **Sensitive Personal Information:** to create a profile about a consumer reflecting the an individual's commercial preferences, predispositions, behavior, and attitudes.
* * **log-in information** (e.g., username and password to online account with Company)
        
    * **Recipients:** Service Providers (e.g., general IT, cloud computing, software, and other business vendors, and data processors), other members of our corporate group, and/or other parties (e.g., litigants and government entities).
    * **Sale/Share:** N/A.

Because there are numerous types of Personal Data in each category, and various uses for each Personal Data type, actual retention periods vary. We retain specific Personal Data pieces based on how long we have a legitimate purpose for the retention. For more information regarding our retention practices, click [here](#HowDataCollect). Generally, we process your Personal Data to provide you services and as otherwise related to the operation of our business, including for one or more of the following business purposes: performing services; managing interactions and transactions; security; debugging; advertising and marketing; quality assurance; processing interactions and transactions; and research and development. We may also use Personal Data for other business purposes in a context that is not a sale or share under applicable U.S. Privacy Laws, such as disclosing it to our service providers, contractors, or processors that perform services for us (“Service Providers”), to you or to other parties at your direction or through your action; for the additional purposes explained at the time of collection (such as in the applicable privacy policy or notice); as required or permitted by applicable law; to the government or private parties to comply with law or legal process or protect or enforce legal rights or obligations or prevent harm; and to assignees as part of an acquisition, merger, asset sale, or other transaction where another party assumes control over all or part of our business (“Additional Business Purposes”). Subject to restrictions and obligations under applicable U.S. Privacy Laws, our Service Providers may also use your Personal Data for Business Purposes and Additional Business Purposes, and may engage subcontractors to enable them to perform services for us.

#### What sources did we obtain Personal Data from and for what reasons did we collect it and do we process it?

Please re-review [this part](#PersonalData) of this Privacy Statement to understand the scope of purposes and the sources from which we collect and for which we process Personal Data.

#### Your U.S. State Privacy Rights

As described more below, subject to meeting the requirements for a Verifiable Consumer Request (defined below) and limitations permitted by applicable U.S. Privacy Law, we provide individuals the privacy rights described in this section, as required by applicable U.S. Privacy Law. Although we have concluded that we are subject only to CCPA and TDPSA (when effective), we will accept requests from consumers under any of the U.S. Privacy Laws, and from residents in states without privacy rights, but will apply our discretion with respect to, and if and how, we process such requests. We will also consider applying state law rights prior to the effective date of such laws, but will do so in our discretion. If you exercise these rights, we will not discriminate against you by treating you differently from other individuals who use our Online and Mobile Resources or purchase our services but did not exercise their rights.

Under CCPA, a consumer includes persons in their capacity as our Workforce and Job Applicants, so accordingly this "Your U.S. State Privacy Rights" section also applies to them. It does not, however, apply to our Workforce or Job Applicants that are not current California residents.

* **Know –** California consumers have the right to request that we disclose to you, specifically beyond the general statement immediately above, the categories of Personal Data collected including the source of the data, our use of it and, if the data was disclosed or sold to third parties, the categories so disclosed or sold as well as the categories of third parties who received or purchased it. This is not applicable in Texas and we reserve the right to limit this to California consumers.
* **Access –** You have the right to receive a copy of the categories and specific elements of Personal Data we collected about you in the preceding 12 months.
* **Correct –** You have the right to request the correction of inaccurate information collected. You can also make changes to your online account in the account settings section of the account. That will not, however, change your information that exists in other places.
* **Delete –** You have the right to request the deletion of Personal Data we collected about you held by us, our Service Providers and any other third party to which we have sold your Personal Data.
* **Opt Out –**You have the right to opt out of any sale, sharing, or targeted advertising of Personal Data (as defined in the CCPA and TDPSA) if such sale / sharing / targeted advertising occurs.
* * Under the CCPA, “share” means to disclose for cross-context behavioral advertising only, and not other forms of disclosure. “Sale” is also broadly defined and does not necessarily need to involve a payment.
    * Due to technical limitations, this opt-out may be exercised separately for cookie and non-cookie data, as explained below.
* **Transfer –**You have the right to request the transfer of specific pieces of Personal Data we have collected about you to another entity.
* **Sensitive Personal Information –**With regard to Personal Data that qualifies as sensitive Personal Data under applicable U.S. Privacy Law, if you elect to provide us with that sensitive Personal Data you will have consented to such processing. We do not process sensitive personal information that is subject to the right to limitation under applicable law. Note, you can terminate your account with us at any time
* **Automated Decision Making / Profiling –** We do not engage in Automated Decision Making or Profiling as defined by U.S. Privacy Laws.

To submit a request to exercise your consumer privacy rights, or to submit a request as an authorized agent, use our [Privacy Rights Request Portal](https://privacyportal-cdn.onetrust.com/dsarwebform/611e70e2-1994-43ff-b07b-646df870db4b/c1c0acac-ab24-4dac-b3e6-43421a684626.html) or [contact us](#PrivacyOffice), and respond to any follow-up inquiries we make. Please be aware that we do not accept or process requests through other means (e.g., via fax, chats, social media etc.). We have the ability to charge a reasonable fee for administrative costs of providing the Personal Data to you in situations where the request is unfounded or excessive (e.g., due to its repeated nature), or in the alternative, we may refuse to act on the request in those situations. We will notify you in such cases

**Opt Out of Sale / Sharing / Targeted Advertising:**

**Opt-out for non-cookie Personal Data:** If you want to limit our processing of your non-cookie Personal Data (e.g., your email address) for targeted advertising, or opt-out of the sale/sharing of such data, make an opt-out request [here](https://privacyportal-cdn.onetrust.com/dsarwebform/611e70e2-1994-43ff-b07b-646df870db4b/c1c0acac-ab24-4dac-b3e6-43421a684626.html).

**Opt-out for cookie Personal Data:** If you want to limit our processing of your cookie-related Personal Data for Targeted Advertising, or opt-out of the Sale/Sharing of such Personal Data, some states allow you to exercise a separate opt-out request by clicking the Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information link that can be found for such states in the bottom footer of the site for which you wish to manage cookies. This is because we have to use different technologies to apply your opt-out of cookie Personal Data and to non-cookie Personal Data. Our cookie management tool enables you to exercise such an opt-out request and enable certain cookie preferences on your device. You must exercise your preferences on each of our Online and Mobile Resources you visit, from each browser you use, and on each device that you use. Since your browser opt-out is designated by a cookie, if you clear or block cookies, your preferences will no longer be effective, and you will need to enable them again via our cookie management tool. Beware that if you use ad blocking software, our cookie banner may not appear when you visit our services, and you may have to use the link above (the Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information link at the bottom of our Online and Mobile Resources) to access the tool.

**Out Preference Signals:** You may also opt out of cookie-related sales / sharing / targeted advertising by using an opt-out preference signal or Global Privacy Control (“GPC”). To use a GPC, you can download an internet browser or a plugin to use on your current internet browser and follow the settings to enable the GPC. We have configured the settings of our consent management platform to receive and process GPC signals on our Online and Mobile Resources. If you opt-out using the GPC functionality available in some browsers while you are logged in to one of our Online and Mobile Resources, we will use that signal to opt you out of all online and offline marketing and sharing. If your browser functionality supports GPC but you are not logged into one of our Online and Mobile Resources we will use that signal to opt you out of online tracking only. If your browser does not support GPC you can click on the Your Privacy Choices link at the bottom of our Online and Mobile Resources to activate our cookie manager where you can select your opt out choices for browser activity. If you email or write us with an opt out request, we will use that request to opt you out of all offline based marketing and sharing and any online based marketing and sharing when you are logged into your account in one of our Online and Mobile Resources. We currently do not, due to technical limitations, process GPC for opt-outs of sales and sharing in other contexts (e.g., non-cookie PI) , except if you are logged into one of our online and mobile resources. We do not: (1) charge a fee for use of our service if you have enabled GPC; (2) change your experience with any product or service if you use GPC; or (3) display a notification, pop-up, text, graphic, animation, sound, video, or any interstitial in response to the GP

We do not knowingly sell or share the Personal Data of consumers under 16. If you think we may have unknowingly collected Personal Data of a consumer under 16 years old, please [Contact Us.](#PrivacyOffice) For more information regarding Children's Information, click [here.](#ChildrenPrivacy)

As permitted or required by applicable U.S. Privacy Laws, any request you submit to us must be a Verifiable Consumer Request, meaning when you make a request, we may ask you to provide verifying information, such as your name, e-mail, phone number and/or account information. We will review the information provided and may request additional information (e.g., transaction history) via e-mail or other means to ensure we are interacting with the correct individual. We will not fulfill your Right to Know (Categories), Right to Know (Specific Pieces), Right to Delete, or Right to Correction request unless you have provided sufficient information for us to reasonably verify you are the consumer about whom we collected Personal Data. We do not verify opt-outs of Sell/Share/Target or Limitation of Sensitive Personal Data requests unless we suspect fraud. To protect individuals’ privacy, if we are unable to verify you sufficiently, we will be unable to honor your request. We will verify your access request to a reasonably high level of certainty, meaning that we may match three data points provided by you with data points maintained by us, which we have determined to be reliable for the purpose of verifying you. We verify a California request to know categories to a reasonable degree of certainty, which may include matching at least two data points provided by you with data points maintained by us, which we have determined to be reliable for the purpose of verifying you. If we cannot do so, we will refer you to this Statement for a general description of our data practices. We verify your request to delete to a reasonable degree of certainty, which may include matching at least two reliable data points provided by you with data points maintained by us, or to a reasonably high degree of certainty, which may include matching at least three reliable data points provided by you with data points maintained by us, depending on the sensitivity of the Personal Data and the risk of harm to the consumer posed by unauthorized deletion. If we cannot verify you sufficiently to honor a deletion request, you can still make a do not sell/share/target and/or limit sensitive Personal Data request. We verify your correction request to a reasonable degree of certainty, which may include matching at least two reliable data points provided by you with data points maintained by us, or to a reasonably high degree of certainty, which may include matching at least three reliable data points provided by you with data points maintained by us, depending on the sensitivity of the Personal Data and the risk of harm to the consumer posed by unauthorized correction.

We will use Personal Data provided in a Verifiable Consumer Request only to verify your identity or authority to make the request and to track and document request responses, unless you also gave it to us for another purpose.

You may use an authorized agent to make a request for you, subject to our verification of the agent, the agent’s authority to submit requests on your behalf, and of you. You can learn how to do this by visiting the agent section of our [Consumer Rights Request Portal.](https://privacyportal-cdn.onetrust.com/dsarwebform/611e70e2-1994-43ff-b07b-646df870db4b/c1c0acac-ab24-4dac-b3e6-43421a684626.html) Once your agent’s authority is confirmed, they may exercise rights on your behalf subject to the agency requirements of applicable U.S. Privacy Laws.

You are not required to create a password-protected account with us to make a Verifiable Consumer Request, but you may use your password-protected account to do so. If we suspect fraudulent or malicious activity on or from the password-protected account, we may decline a request or request that you provide further verifying information.

#### Financial Incentives

We do not currently offer discounts or rewards to individuals for providing us Personal Data, or set price or service differences related to the collection, retention, sale, or sharing of Personal Data. If we offer such programs in the future, we will update this Statement to describe such program(s), including how you may opt-in and how we value the Personal Data required.

#### California Minors

Although our services are intended for an audience over the age of majority, any California residents under the age of eighteen (18) who have registered to use our services, and posted content on the service, can request removal by contacting us [here](#PrivacyOffice), detailing where the content is posted and attesting you posted it. We will then make reasonable, good faith efforts to remove the post from prospective public view or anonymize it, so the minor cannot be individually identified to the extent required by applicable law. This removal process cannot ensure complete or comprehensive removal. For instance, third parties may have republished or archived content by search engines we do not control.

#### Shine the Light

We may disclose “personal information,” as defined by California's “Shine the Light” law, to third parties for such third parties own direct marketing purposes. California residents may opt-out of this sharing by contacting us at [\[email protected\]](https://slashdotmedia.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) [\[email protected\]](https://slashdotmedia.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or Slashdot Media, LLC, PO Box 12190, San Diego, CA 92122 (Attn: Privacy Compliance). You must put the statement “Shine the Light Request” in the body of your correspondence. In your request, please attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for your response. This right is different than, and in addition to, CCPA rights, and must be requested separately. However, a Do Not Sell/Share/Target opt-out is broader and will limit our disclosing to third parties for their own direct marketing purposes without the need for making a separate Shine the Light request. We will not accept Shine the Light requests by telephone or by fax, and are not responsible for requests not labeled or sent properly, or that are incomplete.

#### Your Rights and Our Obligations Under Nevada Privacy Law

If you are Nevada resident, Nevada law (SB 220), entitles you to opt out of the sale of certain kinds of Personal Data. A sale under Nevada law is the transfer of Personal Data to third parties for monetary consideration. If you are a Nevada resident and wish to opt-out, you may do so by contacting us at any of the 4 methods [here](#PrivacyOffice) or click on the Opt-Out link at the bottom of our Online and Mobile Resources.

#### Your Rights and Our Obligations under the GDPR

When we collect Personal Data from individuals located in the European Economic Area, Switzerland, or the United Kingdom (the **"GDPR Jurisdictions"**), those individuals have rights under the GDPR. This section of our Statement is used to fulfill our GDPR obligations and explain your GDPR rights. For purposes of this section, the words **"you"** and **"your"** mean only such individuals located in the GDPR Jurisdictions.

#### Our Collection, Use, and Disclosure Practices

Please review [this section](#PersonalData) to understand the scope of purposes and the sources from which we collect Personal Data. Similarly, you can find data about the categories of third parties with which we may disclose your Personal Data and why we disclose it in[this section](#HowLong). We do not use your Personal Data for automated decision-making subject to the right to request human intervention. We do, however, collect certain Personal Data from you for the purpose of selling it subject to having obtained your consent if required under applicable law. We also collect certain Personal Data from third parties. If we are reasonably aware that such third parties have not provided you with appropriate notice of collection by us, we will provide you the required alternate notice under Article 14 of the GDPR when we first contact you using such data or before one month has elapsed, whichever occurs first. We typically provide that Article 14 notice in the body of the communication used to contact you.

#### Legal Basis for Processing Your Personal Data

Our legal basis for collecting and using your Personal Data will depend on the Personal Data concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. However, we will normally collect Personal Data where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms, such as to contact you about products and services you may be interested in. In certain circumstances where our legal basis for processing is for performance of a contract with you, please be aware that, in those circumstances, where you do not provide Personal Data, which is required by us, we will not be able to provide the products and services under our contract with you or your company or may not be able to comply with a legal obligation on us. In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect Personal Data from you or may otherwise need the Personal Data to protect your vital interests or those of another person. If we happen to obtain your consent to process your Personal Data, you may withdraw your consent at any time via any of the means listed [here](#PrivacyOffice). Detailed information regarding the applicable legal basis for processing your Personal Data is provided in this Statement below.

| ### Data voluntarily provided by you when you register on our Online and Mobile Resources, create a free or paid listing, fill out a form, write a review, write a comment, interact with Online and Mobile Resources tools, upload images or content, connect with a Slashdot Media sales representative, correspond with us via e-mail or mail, or subscribe to one of our email lists. This data is directly provided by you. |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Categories of Personal Data we collect voluntarily from you include:**<br><br>* Personal Data such as your full name and contact details such as the name of your company, the state and county in which you are based, your business email address, telephone number, and job title;<br>* Your company website URL;<br>* What you are interested in hearing about (e.g., lead generation or website review);<br>* What advertising channels you use such as pay per click, pay per view, fixed or other advertising channels;<br>* Data about the software you offer (e.g., the product name, type of software and product description);<br>* Data we require so we may invoice you, including your payment details and billing data;<br>* Other data you provide when you communicate with us, including your full name, contact details and business email address, phone number, and details of our communications;<br>* Other information and data you may provide when writing a review, submitting a forum or blog post, submitting a comment, submitting a support or bug ticket, editing a wiki, uploading files or images, open-source code, or inbound emailing to an open-source project list; and<br>* Other data you provide when you communicate with us including your full name, contact details and business email address, phone number and details of any such communications. |     |
| **We use this Personal Data for certain activities, including:** | **We use this Personal Data because:** |
| Fulfilling your requests, for example, to publish your company's listing and other submitted content, to provide your company with details of leads (including their name, data about their business, software requirements and follow up next steps (e.g., request demo)), and to invoice your company appropriately. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Manage and promote our business and brand;<br>* Provide and improve our services;<br>* Operate our business; and<br><br>Obtain payment for our services. |
| Managing your profile and listings. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Provide and improve our services;<br>* Operate our business; and<br>* Improve the performance and user experience of our Online and Mobile Resources.<br><br>We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Provide and improve our services; and<br>* Operate our business. |
| Sending you service emails (e.g., service announcements and messages relating to your account). |
| Providing consultation services. |
| Verifying the validity of your review(s) and ensuring that false, misleading, or malicious reviews are not posted. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to monitor, investigate and prevent any attempts to damage our reputation/ business interests. |
| Sending you email including, but not limited to, service announcements, account related messages, project related updates, and subscribed newsletters. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to manage and promote our business and brand in order to increase our sales.<br><br>You **consented.** You have the right to withdraw this consent by contacting the Data Protection Officer or using the unsubscribe mechanism provided with each communication. |
| Sending marketing information and offers to business contacts regarding SMD services. |
| Notifying you about special offers available from us, our affiliates, or partners, which may be of interest to you. |
| Inviting you to provide reviews about other products and services, and to consider other services provided by SMD. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Manage and promote our business and brand;<br>* Provide and improve our services;<br>* Operate our business; and<br>* Improve the performance and user experience of our Online and Mobile Resources. |
| Providing our services and managing our Online and Mobile Resources (including any compatible processing to otherwise operate our business). | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Manage and promote our business and brand;<br>* Provide and improve our services;<br>* Operate our business; and<br>* Improve the performance and user experience of our Online and Mobile Resources. |
| Responding to your questions, investigating any complaints, and providing customer service. | * We need to process your data to satisfy your requests (**performance of a contract**); or<br>* We have a **legitimate business interest** to resolve any concerns or disputes you may have. |
| Administering our Online and Mobile Resources and our other products and services (including any compatible processing to otherwise operate our business). | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Provide and improve our services; and<br>* Operate our business |
| Customizing your digital experience. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Promote our business and brand;<br>* Improve our services;<br>* Operate our business; and<br>* Improve the performance and user experience of our Online and Mobile Resources. |
| Investigating complaints, providing customer service, and resolving disputes. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Provide and improve our services;<br>* Operate our business;<br>* Monitor, investigate, and report any attempts to breach the security of our Online and Mobile Resources; and<br>* Resolve any concerns or disputes you may have and defend our legitimate interests and protect the company and its shareholders and directors. |
| For internal analytical and research purposes to help us to measure interest in and improve our services | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Manage and promote our business and brand;<br>* Improve our services; and<br>* Improve the performance and user experience of our Online and Mobile Resources. |
| Preventing prohibited or illegal activities. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to monitor, investigate, prevent, and report any attempts to breach the security of our Online and Mobile Resources. |
| Enforcing our policies or terms. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to ensure compliance with the company policies and processes for protecting our business interests and complying with legal obligations. |
| In connection with leads and ads, to disclose it to our business customers and Third-Party Digital Businesses for their own marketing purposes. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to manage and promote our business and brand in order to increase our sales. |
| To comply with any legal requirement or following any mandatory legal process. | **Compliance with a legal obligation.** |

| ### Data we collect about your use of our Online and Mobile Resources (Automatically Collected) |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Categories of Personal Data we collect automatically about you include:**<br><br>* Data recorded in our logs, including URL, IP address, browser and OS data, timestamp, referring site, geolocation, and other standard browser data;<br>* Behavioral data (such as data on the behavior or presumed interests of individuals which are linked to those individuals and may be used to create a user profile) pages viewed, images viewed, documents downloaded, and links to other sites followed; and<br>* Data captured by our cookies (see our [Cookie Policy](https://slashdotmedia.com/opt-out-choices/)). |     |
| **We use this Personal Data for certain activities, including:** | **We use this Personal Data because:** |
| To personalize your experience on our Online and Mobile Resources.<br><br>To operate our Online and Mobile Resources, develop, and improve our products and services for you and for our business customers (including any compatible processing to otherwise operate our business).<br><br>Analytical, statistical and trend analysis to improve the user experience and performance of our Online and Mobile Resources.<br><br>To facilitate your access to and use of our Online and Mobile Resources. | You **consented.** You have the right to withdraw this consent at any time by clicking the Privacy Choices link that can be found in the bottom footer of the site for which you wish to manage cookies. |
| Resolving disputes and troubleshooting problems. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Resolve any concerns or disputes you may have and defend our legitimate interests and protect the company and its shareholders and directors; and<br>* Resolve any issues relating to the Service so that we can comply with our customer contracts. |
| In connection with leads and ads, to disclose it with our business customers and Third Party Digital Businesses for their own marketing purposes. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to manage and promote our business and brand in order to increase our sales.<br><br>* Resolve any concerns or disputes you may have and defend our legitimate interests and protect the company and its shareholders and directors; and<br>* Resolve any issues relating to the Service so that we can comply with our customer contracts. |
| To comply with any legal requirement or following any mandatory legal proces | **Compliance with a legal obligation.** |

| ### Data that we Collect from Other Sources |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Categories of Personal Data we collect about you include:**<br><br>* Contact data, such as name, email address, mailing address and phone number, as well as potentially workplace and job title of the contact persons at prospective customers;<br>* Uniquely identifiable mobile device data;<br>* Geolocation data;<br>* Data collected by third-party tracking technologies, including:<br>    * URL, IP address, browser and OS data, timestamp, referring site, and other standard browser data;<br>    * Behavioral data (such as data on the behavior or presumed interests of individuals which are linked to those individuals and may be used to create a user profile) pages viewed, images viewed, documents downloaded, and links to other sites followed; and<br>    * Behavioral data from interactions with third-party social media sites and applications<br>* Data collected from third-party mail services (as described above). |     |
| **We use this Personal Data for certain activities, including:** | **We use this Personal Data because:** |
| Identifying prospective customers. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to promote our business and brand. |
| Managing customer relationships (including any compatible processing to otherwise operate our business). | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Provide and improve our services; and<br>* Operate our business. |
| Sending you service emails (e.g., service announcements and messages relating to your account). | We have a **legitimate business interest** to manage and promote our business and brand in order to increase our sales.<br><br>* Provide and improve our services;<br>* Operate our business; and<br>* Improve the performance and user experience of our Online and Mobile Resources. |
| Providing consultation services. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to manage and promote our business and brand in order to increase our sales.<br><br>* Provide and improve our services; and<br>* Operate our business. |
| Managing your profile and listings. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to manage and promote our business and brand in order to increase our sales.<br><br>* Provide and improve our services;<br>* Operate our business; and<br>* Improve the performance and user experience of our Online and Mobile Resources. |
| Notifying you about special offers available from us, our affiliates, or partners, which may be of interest to you. | You consented. You have the right to withdraw this consent by contacting the Data Protection Officer or using the unsubscribe mechanism provided with each communication. |
| Sending marketing to business contacts regarding our services and products which may be of interest and to promote our business and brand. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to manage and promote our business and brand. |
| Responding to your questions and requests and otherwise customizing your digital experience. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Manage and promote our business and brand;<br>* Provide and improve our services; and<br>* Operate our business. |
| For internal analysis and research to help us to measure interest in and improve our services and other products and services of our customers. |
| Preventing prohibited or illegal activities. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to monitor, investigate, and prevent any attempts to damage our reputation or business interests. |
| Enforcing our policies or terms. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to ensure compliance with company policies and processes for protecting our business interests and complying with legal obligations. |
| In connection with leads and ads, to disclose it with our business customers and Third-Party Digital Businesses for their own marketing purposes. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to manage and promote our business and brand in order to increase our sales. |
| For complying with any legal requirement or following any mandatory legal process. | **Compliance with a legal obligation.** |

#### Your GDPR Privacy Rights

You may exercise the rights available to you under the GDPR, including the [right to object](#ObjectProcessing) to the processing of your Personal Data, as follows:

* **Access –** the right to obtain a confirmation that your Personal Data is being processed, access to your Personal Data (if we are in fact processing it), other data about the processing of your Personal Data (most of which is set forth in this Statement), and a copy of the Personal Data we are processing.
* **Rectification –** the right to have your Personal Data corrected if it is inaccurate, and depending on the purposes of processing, you may also have incomplete Personal Data completed.
* **Erasure –** also known as the “right to be forgotten,” the right to request your Personal Data be deleted under certain circumstances such as if it is no longer needed for the original purpose it was collected for or if you withdraw your consent. The right of erasure does not apply under limited circumstances including if the processing is necessary for exercising the right of freedom of expression and data or our compliance with a legal obligation.
* **Restrict processing –** the right to restrict processing of your Personal Data under certain circumstances such as if you contest the accuracy of the Personal Data (and only for so long as it takes to verify that accuracy), the processing is unlawful and you have requested restriction of the processing rather than erasure, or if we no longer need the Personal Data but you need it to establish, exercise, or defend a legal claim.
* **Portability –** the right to receive the Personal Data you provided to us (and not any other data) under limited circumstances such as if the basis for processing the Personal Data was consent or necessary for the performance of a contract with you, or the processing is carried out by automated means.
* **Automated Processing –** SDM does not engage in automated decision-making activities subject to the right to opt out under the GDPR.
* **Object to processing –** the right to object to the processing of your Personal Data under the following circumstances:
    * Legitimate Interests – if the basis for which the processing occurs is in our legitimate interests or in the performance of a task carried out in the public interest. If you object, we will stop processing your Personal Data unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights, and freedoms or we require the Personal Data to establish, exercise or defend a legal claim.
    * Direct Marketing – if the processing is for direct marketing purposes.

You can exercise these rights by contacting us using the contact data listed [here,](#SDM) however, we may need to request additional data from you to verify your identity before granting your request. We will respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise such rights in accordance with the GDPR. We have the ability to charge a reasonable fee for administrative costs of providing the Personal Data to you in situations where the request is unfounded or excessive (e.g., due to its repeated nature), or in the alternative, we may refuse to act on the request in those situations. We will notify you in such cases.

#### Lodging a Complaint

You have the right to complain to your data protection authority about our collection and use of your Personal Data. Please contact your local data protection authority for more information. Contact data for data protection authorities can be found [here](https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/board/members_en) and [here](https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/).

#### Retaining Your Personal Data

As more fully set forth above, we will store and retain your Personal Data in accordance with applicable law and as long as necessary to carry out the purposes described in this section in accordance with our internal data retention procedures. The criteria used to determine the retention periods include:

* how long the Personal Data is needed in connection with the applicable purposes for which we use it;
* the type of Personal Data collected; and
* whether we are subject to a legal, contractual, or similar obligation to retain the Personal Data (e.g., mandatory data retention laws, government orders to preserve Personal Data relevant to an investigation, or Personal Data that must be retained for the purposes of litigation or disputes).

#### Cross-Border Data Transfer

By submitting Personal Data to us, we will receive it in the United States where our technical infrastructure resides. We undertake such collection solely for the purposes described previously in this Statement but note that such direct collection does not constitute a “transfer” under the GDPR. In certain instances, we collect Personal Data from data subjects located within the GDPR Jurisdictions, and do then transfer it to the U.S., to international organizations, and/or to third countries for the same purposes discussed above. When doing so, may use the mechanisms prescribed for lawful transfers in GDPR Articles 44 through 49, including, where appropriate, then-current standard contractual clauses or similar mechanism appropriate to the particular GDPR Jurisdiction involved. You can request further details in relation to international transfers, including a copy of the standard contractual clauses, by contacting us [here](#SDM).

Notwithstanding anything herein to the contrary, with respect to Personal Data that our business customers transfer to us from the EU, UK, or Switzerland, (i) our Data Privacy Framework Policy applies and provides those data subjects additional rights (you can review our [DPF Policy](https://slashdotmedia.com/dpf-policy/) and learn how to make DPF requests); and/or (ii) to the extent that your Personal Data was transferred to the U.S. pursuant to the standard contractual clauses, such clauses control with respect to our processing of such Personal Data.

### CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT

We reserve the right to change or update this Statement from time to time. Please check our Online and Mobile Resources periodically for such changes since all data collected is subject to the Statement in place at the time of collection. We will indicate the effective/amendment date at the beginning of this Statement.

### HOW TO CONTACT OUR PRIVACY OFFICE

If you have any questions about our privacy and data security policies, procedures, and practices, including anything we say in this Privacy Statement, we encourage you to contact our Privacy Office.

Slashdot Media, LLC

* Address: PO Box 12190 San Diego, CA 92122
* Attn: Privacy Compliance
* Phone: 1-800-552-9000 or +1-858-454-5900 x10804
* Portals: [Info Request and Data Deletion](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/webform/611e70e2-1994-43ff-b07b-646df870db4b/f4165d65-f39c-4ea5-8628-163090b74137) and [Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information](https://privacyportal-cdn.onetrust.com/dsarwebform/611e70e2-1994-43ff-b07b-646df870db4b/c1c0acac-ab24-4dac-b3e6-43421a684626.html)
* Email: [\[email protected\]](https://slashdotmedia.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

### OUR REPRESENTATIVE IN THE EU

_**General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) – European Representative**  
Pursuant to Article 27 of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR),_ **Slashdot Media,  
LLC** _has appointed European Data Protection Office (EDPO) as its GDPR Representative in  
the EU. You can contact EDPO regarding matters pertaining to the GDPR:  
\-by using EDPO’s online request form: [https://edpo.com/gdpr-data-request/](https://edpo.com/gdpr-data-request/)  
\-by writing to EDPO at at Regus Block 1, Blanchardstown Corporate Park, Ballycoolen Road,  
Blanchardstown, Dublin, D15 AKK1, Ireland  
_

### OUR REPRESENTATIVE IN THE UK

_**UK General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) - UK Representative**  
Pursuant to Article 27 of the UK GDPR,_ **Slashdot Media, LLC** _has appointed EDPO UK Ltd  
as its UK GDPR representative in the UK. You can contact EDPO UK regarding matters  
pertaining to the UK GDPR:  
\- by using EDPO’s online request form: [https://edpo.com/uk-gdpr-data-request/](https://edpo.com/uk-gdpr-data-request/)  
\- by writing to EDPO UK at 8 Northumberland Avenue, London WC2N 5BY, United Kingdom  
_

### Index

[❖ What Personal Data Do We Collect About You And How Do We Use It?](#PersonalData)

* [♦ What sources did we obtain Personal Data from and for what reasons did we collect it and do we process it?](#personalReasons)

### NEW PRIVACY AND DATA SECURITY STATEMENT

This Privacy Statement was amended as of February 14th 2024 and is effective as of that date.

Thank you for visiting Slashdot Media's Online and Mobile Resources (defined below), and for viewing this Privacy Statement. This Privacy Statement applies to any online and mobile resource that links to this Statement, including SlashdotMedia.com, SourceForge.net, and Slashdot.org, Our full Privacy Statement, contained in the pages that follow, serves to give notice to data subjects, other than our _Workforce and Job Applicants_ (defined below), about the types of Personal Data (defined below) we collect as a controller, how we use it, who we disclose it with and why, your rights with respect to your Personal Data, and what we do to try to protect it. In addition, the [Cross-Border Data Transfer](#CrossBorderData) section addresses certain Personal Data we receive from our business customers to process in connections with providing them services that is imported to the United States from certain European territories. We encourage you to read our full Statement carefully. _Workforce and Job Applicants_ can obtain a copy of a notice of the data practices that apply to them by contacting us [here.](#PrivacyOffice) This Statement also outlines privacy rights and options that you may have, and how to exercise them, including for our Workforce and Job Applicants, as more fully set forth in [Your U.S. State Privacy Rights](#CCPA), [Your GDPR Privacy Rights](#exercisingYourRights) and our [DPF Policy](https://slashdotmedia.com/dpf-policy/) . Click here for a table of contents that allows you to link to specific sections.

### SOME IMPORTANT VOCABULARY

Although not itself a contract, this Privacy Statement is an important document that explains how we address some of our legal obligations, and your related legal rights, involving Personal Data. Clarity is, therefore, important. We will use this section to let you know about some words that have special meanings whenever you see them in this Statement.

Let's start with the word **"Statement"** itself: when we reference **"this Statement"**, **"this Privacy Statement"** and **"our Statement"**, we mean the Privacy Statement you are reading now. Wherever we say **"Company"**, **"we"**, **"us"**, **"our"**, or **"SDM"**, we mean Slashdot Media LLC or its affiliates, as applicable.

When we talk about our **"Online and Mobile Resources"**, we mean all websites, portals, or other features SDM operates, that link to this Statement. SDM also offers certain business-to-business marketing and advertising services. When we refer to **"Lead Ads and Content"** we mean the special types of advertisements and other content, such as whitepapers and email contents, containing forms or other means for users to provide information showing their interest in the applicable product or service. The term **"Affinity Action"** means when you "follow" us, "like" us or take a similar or analogous action on our external social media presence.

Finally, and perhaps most importantly, when we refer to **"Personal Data"** we mean information that identifies or can be used to reasonably identify you, or that is otherwise treated as personal information or Personal Data under applicable laws (for example, IP address, cookie IDs, device IDs). Where information does not qualify as Personal Data under applicable law (e.g., information that has been anonymized, or aggregated), we will not treat it as such.

### WHO DOES THIS STATEMENT APPLY TO?

This Statement describes our Personal Data practices regarding the following groups of data subjects:

* individuals that visit, use, access, or interact with our Online and Mobile Resources and/or Lead Ads and Content (**"Visitors and Users"**);
* contact persons and representatives of customers of our advertising, marketing and lead generation services (**"Customer Personnel"**); and
* contact persons and representatives of our third-party vendors and business partners (**"Vendor and Business Partner Personnel"**).

The categories of data we collect from each of these groups, and the ways in which we use it, differs.

While our data practices regarding our current and former personnel and job applicants (**"Workforce and Job Applicants"**) are described in a separate notice and not this Statement, this Statement does explain how those data subjects can exercise their privacy rights under applicable law. With the exception of our [DPF Policy](https://slashdotmedia.com/dpf-policy/) and the [Cross-Border Data Transfer](#CrossBorderData) section, this Statement does not include Personal Data we do not control but may process for our business customers to provide them services.

#### Our Visitors and Users

This Privacy Statement applies to Visitors and Users of our Online and Mobile Resources and those that interact with our lead generation ads and content including content we may send as part of email campaigns.

#### Our Customers and Customer Personnel

Our business customers enter into contracts with us. That contract is separate from this Statement and has its own terms and conditions for processing of Personal Data on their behalf and governing our overall confidentiality, data privacy and data security obligations. As a result, those terms, and not this Statement, apply to the Personal Data of business customers that we process for them. However, we independently collect and process for ourselves Personal Data of Customer Personnel, and this Statement covers that. In addition, our [DPF Policy](https://slashdotmedia.com/dpf-policy/) and the [Cross-Border Data Transfer](#CrossBorderData) section covers certain Personal Data of our business customers that we import to the U.S. to process in connection with providing them services.

#### Our Workforce and Job Applicants

We collect and retain the types of professional or employment related Personal Data you would expect an employer to have about its workforce and job applicants, however, rather than describe those practices in this Statement, we provide legally required notices of collection and describe our use and sharing of the Personal Data of our Workforce and Applicants in greater detail in a separate notice. Contact us [here](#PrivacyOffice) for more information. However, this Statement does explain how our Workforce and Job Applicants may exercise their privacy rights under applicable law.

#### Our Vendors and Business Partners

Like all corporate enterprises, we buy goods and services, lease equipment and office space and attend industry events. In doing so, we interact with personnel of existing and potential Vendors from whom we necessarily collect certain Personal Data. We describe our use of Vendor and Business Partner Personnel Personal Data that we control generally in this Statement; provided, however, that our confidential contracts with those parties may address other Personal Data processing relating to those parties.

### WHAT PERSONAL DATA DO WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU AND HOW DO WE USE IT?

We collect the Personal Data we control in three ways: (i) Personal Data you voluntarily provide to us; (ii) Personal Data we collect through automated/technical means; and (iii) Personal Data that we collect from publicly available sources or obtain from third parties. We may also infer other Personal Data from the Personal Data that we collect and control. We describe our Personal Data processing practices regarding each of those collection methods in the tables below. Additional detail is provided in the [Comprehensive Privacy Laws](#ComprehensiveLaws) section that provide required notices to residents of certain U.S. states and for the UK, European Economic Area and Switzerland.

**_By using our Online and Mobile Resources, you are signifying to us that you have read and understand this Privacy Statement._**

We provide more detailed descriptions of our Personal Data practices by source in the charts below. However, regardless of source, SMD may use your Personal Data for any purposes not inconsistent with our statements under this Privacy Statement, or otherwise made by us in writing at the point of collection, and not prohibited by applicable law, including, without limitation, to:

* allow you to participate in the features we offer on our Online and Mobile Resources;
* facilitate, manage, personalize, and improve your user experience;
* process your registration, manage your account, and/or upload your user generated content;
* transact with you, provide services or information you request, respond to your comments, questions and requests, serve you content and/or advertising, and send you notices;
* market to you and other promotional purposes;
* sell to our business customers, subject to limitations, as more fully explained [here;](#rightsToKnow)
* improve our products and service and for other internal business purposes;
* tailor our content, advertisements, and offers;
* fulfill other purposes disclosed at the time you provide your Personal Data or otherwise where we are legally permitted or required to do so;
* determine your location and manage digital content (e.g., territory restrictions or customization); and
* prevent and address fraud, breach of policies or terms, and threats of harm, enforce rights and/or comply with law and legal process.

Without limiting the generality of the forgoing, please see the following sections below regarding distinctions between Voluntarily Submitted Data, Automatically Collected Data, and Data Collected from Other Sources.

#### Voluntarily Submitted Data

If you choose to participate in or make use of certain activities and features available via our Online and Mobile Resources, you will need to provide us with data about yourself. The types of Personal Data you will be submitting to us in those situations is almost always limited to basic identifiers such as your name, email address, mailing address, and phone number. Below are some of the ways you voluntarily give us your Personal Data and information on how and why we use it:

| ### Data we collect voluntarily provided by you when you register on our site, create or claim a free or paid listing, connect with Slashdot Media sales representatives, fill out a form, write a review, write a comment, interact with website tools, upload images or content, e-mail us or subscribe to one of our email lists. This data is directly provided by you. |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Categories of Personal Data we collect voluntarily from you include:** | * If you register as a user, we collect Personal Data such as your full name, business or personal email address, job title, the name of your company, industry sector, the state/county in which you are based, business email address, your telephone number, and job title;<br>* You may provide Personal Data when writing a review, submitting a forum or blog post, submitting a comment, submitting a support or bug ticket, editing a wiki, uploading files or images, open-source code, or inbound emailing to an open-source project list;<br>* Your company website URL;<br>* What you are interested in hearing about (e.g., lead generation or website review);<br>* What advertising channels you use such as pay per click, pay per view, fixed, or other advertising channels;<br>* Data about the software you offer (e.g., the product name, type of software, and product description);<br>* Data we require so we may invoice you, including your payment details and billing data; and<br>* You may also provide Personal Data when you communicate with us including your full name, contact details and business email address, phone number and details of any such communications. |
| **We use this Personal Data in connection with our business, including:** | * Fulfilling your requests, for example, to publish your listing and other submitted content, to provide you with details of leads (including their name, data about their business, software requirements and follow up next steps (e.g., request a demo)), and to invoice you appropriately;<br>* Managing your profile and listings;<br>* Providing consultation services;<br>* Verifying the validity of your review(s) and blocking false, misleading, malicious, obscene, or otherwise objectionable content;<br>* Sending you email including, but not limited to service announcements, account related messages, project related updates, and subscribed newsletters;<br>* Sending marketing information and offers to business contacts regarding Slashdot Media services;<br>* Notifying you about special offers available from us, our affiliates or partners, which may be of interest to you;<br>* Inviting you to provide reviews about other products and services, and to consider other services provided by SMD;<br>* Providing our services, managing our Online and Mobile Resources, responding to your questions, investigating any complaints, and providing customer service;<br>* Administering our services and Online and Mobile Resources, investigating complaints, and providing customer service;<br>* Customizing your digital experience;<br>* Responding to your questions and requests and otherwise customizing your digital experience;<br>* Resolving disputes;<br>* For internal analysis and research purposes to help us to measure interest in and improve our services;<br>* In connection with leads and ads, and subject to applicable law, to disclose it with our customers and Third-Party Digital Businesses for their own marketing purposes;<br>* Preventing prohibited or illegal activities or harm to us or others;<br>* Enforcing our policies or terms;<br>* To otherwise operate our business subject to the limitation of applicable law; and<br>* As required by law or legal process. |
| **We use this Personal Data because:** | * It is necessary to comply with applicable laws or regulations; and/or<br>* To operate our business, including to:<br>* * Manage and promote our business and brand;<br>    * Provide and improve our services;<br>    * Operate our business;<br>    * Improve the performance and user experience of our Online and Mobile Resources;<br>    * Monitor, investigate and report any attempts to breach the security of our Online and Mobile Resources; and<br>    * Resolve any concerns or disputes you may have. |

#### Automatically Collected Data

When you visit or use our Online and Mobile Resources, basic data about your internet/electronic activity is automatically collected through your browser via tracking technologies, such as “cookies.” Cookies are small text files downloaded onto your computer or mobile device. Cookies allow us to collect your IP address and other usage data, recognize your computer or mobile device, and store some data about your preferences for using our Online and Mobile Resources or past actions, such as described in the table below:

| ### Data we collect about your use of our Online and Mobile Resources(Automatically Collected). |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Categories of Personal Data we collect automatically about you include:** | * Data recorded in our logs, including URL, IP address, browser and OS data, timestamp, referring site, geolocation, and other standard browser data;<br>* Behavioral data (such as data on the behavior or presumed interests of individuals which are linked to those individuals and may be used to create a user profile) pages viewed, images viewed, documents downloaded and links to other sites followed; and<br>* Data captured by our cookies (see our [Cookie Policy](https://slashdotmedia.com/opt-out-choices/)). |
| **We use this Personal Data in connection with our business, including:** | * To personalize your experience on our Online and Mobile Resources;<br>* Operating our Online and Mobile Resources, and developing and improving our products and services;<br>* Analytical, statistical, and trend analysis to improve the user experience and performance of our Online and Mobile Resources;<br>* To facilitate your access to and use of our Online and Mobile Resources;<br>* In connection with leads and ads, and subject to applicable law, to disclose it with our customers and Third-Party Digital Businesses for their own marketing purposes;<br>* Resolving disputes and troubleshooting problems;<br>* To otherwise operate our business subject to the limitations of applicable law; and<br>* As required by law or legal process. |
| **We use this Personal Data because:** | * It is necessary to comply with applicable laws or regulations; and/or<br>* We use it to operate our business, including to:<br>* * Monitor, investigate, and report any attempts to breach the security of our Online and Mobile Resources;<br>    * Improve the performance and user experience of our Online and Mobile Resources;<br>    * Develop our product and service offerings for service users and our customers;<br>    * You consented (where required under applicable law) to the use of your data for marketing. Where we rely on your consent, you have the right to withdraw this consent by contacting us via the information below or unsubscribing via the opt-out functionality provided in our marketing communications to you; and<br>    * Resolve any concerns or disputes you may have. |

#### Data Collected from Other Sources

We collect Personal Data from publicly available sources and from third parties (such as data brokers), which we may combine with Personal Data you have provided to us or that we have collected automatically.

| ### Data that we collect from other sources |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Categories of Personal Data we collect about you include:** | * Contact data, such as name, email address, mailing address, and phone number, as well as, potentially, workplace and job title for contact persons at prospective customers;<br>* Uniquely identifiable mobile device data;<br>* Geolocation data;<br>* Data collected by third-party tracking technologies, including:<br>* * URL, IP address, browser and OS data, timestamp, referring site, and other standard browser data;<br>    * Behavioral data (such as data on the behavior or presumed interests of individuals which are linked to those individuals and may be used to create a user profile) pages viewed, images viewed, documents downloaded, and links to other sites followed; and<br>    * Behavioral data from interactions with third-party social media sites and applications.<br>* Data collected from third-party mail services (as described below). |
| **We use this Personal Data in connection with our business, including:** | * Identifying prospective customers;<br>* Managing customer relationships;<br>* Managing your profile and listings;<br>* Sending you service emails (e.g., service announcements and messages relating to your account);<br>* Providing consultation services;<br>* Notifying you about special offers available from us and our affiliates or partners, which may be of interest to you;<br>* Sending marketing to business contacts regarding our services and products which may be of interest and to promote our business and brand;<br>* In connection with leads and ads, and subject to applicable law, to disclose it with our customers and Third-Party Digital Businesses for their own marketing purposes;<br>* Administering our services and Online and Mobile Resources;<br>* Responding to your questions and requests and otherwise customizing your digital experience;<br>* For internal analysis and research to help us to measure interest in and improve our services;<br>* Preventing prohibited or illegal activities;<br>* Enforcing our policies or terms;<br>* To otherwise operate our business subject to the limitation of applicable law; and<br>* As required by law or legal process. |
| **We use this Personal Data because:** | * It is necessary to comply with applicable laws or regulations;<br>* We have a legitimate business interest to:<br>* * Manage and promote our business and brand;<br>    * Provide and improve our services;<br>    * Operate our business;<br>    * Obtain payment for our services;<br>    * Improve the performance and user experience of our Online and Mobile Resources;<br>    * Monitor, investigate, and report any attempts to breach the security of our Online and Mobile Resources; and<br>    * Resolve any concerns or disputes you may have.<br>* You consented (where required under applicable law) to the use of your data for marketing. Where we rely upon your consent, you have the right to withdraw this consent by contacting the Data Protection Officer via the contact details above or unsubscribing via the opt-out functionality provided in our marketing communications to you. |

Additional data about cookies and tracking technologies is available [here](https://www.ftc.gov/policy-notices/privacy-policy/internet-cookies).

If you access our Online and Mobile Resources from a phone or other mobile device, the mobile provider may transmit certain data to us such as uniquely identifiable mobile device data. That, in turn, allows us to collect mobile phone numbers and associate them with the mobile device identification data. You can control some of the information disclosed with us through your device settings.

When you use our Online and Mobile Resources, we may allow third party providers (**"Third-Party Digital Businesses"**) to place their own cookies or similar technologies to engage in the same types of collection we describe above.

As part of our services, we will sometimes initially identify prospective customers via public websites or applications operated by third parties such as [Seamless.ai](https://seamless.ai/) . The type of data we collect is the same as that described above, such as name, email address, mailing address, and phone number, as well as potentially workplace and job title of the contact persons at those prospective customers. We also purchase data sets from third parties and use them to check the accuracy of the data we collected from such public sources. In some cases, we may use the data we purchased from a third party even if we did not previously collect it from a public source. We exercise reasonable care and due diligence in purchasing data from third parties and only do so when we are able to obtain assurances that they obtained Personal Data in a lawful manner.

#### User Beware: External Sites, Apps, Links, and Social Media

We maintain a presence on one or more external social media platforms such as X, Facebook, Instagram, and LinkedIn. We may further allow the community features of our Online and Mobile Resources to connect with, or be viewable from, that external social media presence. Similarly, our Online and Mobile Resources may contain links to other websites or apps controlled by third parties.

If you interact with our Online and Mobile Resources using plug-ins for any social networks, including Facebook, X, or YouTube, your activity may be available for review by those network operators and other users of such social networks.

We and the third-party owning such social network plug-ins process the Personal Data collected from the interaction with such plug-ins as joint controllers. The processing operations that we carry out on a joint controller basis are the collection and communication by transmission to the relevant network operator of Personal Data related to our visitors. Where these third parties carry out further processing operations for their own purposes, they will be considered as the sole data controllers. Where you access our resources from the EEA, UK, or Switzerland, our joint controller agreements with such third parties will apply. These agreements determine the respective responsibilities for compliance with the obligations under the GDPR and equivalent regulations with regard to the joint processing, as specified in the applicable product terms of Facebook, X, and YouTube. Please note that the information collected by means of social network plug-ins used may entail the transfer of your Personal Data by the corresponding third parties to countries outside the European Economic Area. These international transfers of data are controlled in their entirety by the relevant third party as set out in their respective privacy and cookie policies and will generally rely on these social networks being DPF certified.

We are not responsible for the content on, or the privacy practices of, social media platforms, or any third-party sites or apps to which we link. Those apps, sites and platforms are not controlled by us and therefore have their own privacy policies and terms of use. **To be clear: neither this Statement nor the terms of use appearing on or in any of our Online and Mobile Resources apply to our social media presence or any third-party sites or apps to which we may link.** That means even if you take an Affinity Action on our specific social media profile, and identifiers about you are automatically collected and given to us as a result, that collection and transfer is governed by the privacy policies and other terms of the applicable social media platform. If you have questions about how those apps, sites and platforms collect, use and disclose Personal Data, you should carefully read their privacy policies and contact them using the contact information they provide.

### HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR PERSONAL DATA?

We retain your Personal Data for a period of time consistent with the purpose of collection and processing, fulfilling our legal obligations and enforcing our agreements and defending our legitimate interests. The retention period for Personal Data is determined by us based on the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the Personal Data being processed, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of the Personal Data, whether we can achieve the purposes of the processing through other means, and any applicable legal requirements. For example, we will retain certain identifiers for as long as it is necessary to continue maintaining your account and providing you our products and services, to comply with our tax, accounting, and recordkeeping obligations, and for research, development, and safety purposes, as well as an additional period as necessary to protect, defend, or establish our rights, defend against potential claims, and to comply with our legal obligations.

### WHEN AND TO WHOM DO WE DISCLOSE PERSONAL DATA?

We may disclose your Personal Data as described below, subject to the requirements of the Comprehensive Privacy Laws, such as lawful basis for processing under EU/UK/Swiss laws and opt out under U.S. Privacy Laws.

#### Affiliates

Subject to applicable law, we may disclose Personal Data to other corporate affiliates who will use such data in the same way as we can under this Statement.

#### Legal Requirements

We may disclose Personal Data to government authorities, and to other third parties, as required or permitted by law, including responding to court orders and subpoenas.

#### To Prevent Harm

We also may disclose Personal Data when we have reason to believe that someone is causing injury to or interference with our rights or property or harming or potentially harming other persons or property.

#### Business Transactions

If we, or any of our affiliates, sell or transfer all or substantially all of our assets, equity interests or securities, or are acquired by one or more third parties as a result of an acquisition, merger, sale, reorganization, divestiture, consolidation, or liquidation, Personal Data may be one of the transferred assets. Such disclosures may include pre-transaction disclosures such as during due diligence.

#### Vendors and Business Partners

We also disclose Personal Data to service providers, contractors, or processors, and business partners (our **"Vendors"**) who need it to perform services for us under the contracts we have with them, including Third Party Digital Businesses (e.g., operators of cookies and tracking technologies associated with our Online and Mobile Resources).

#### Customers

As a data-driven business-to-business demand generation marketing and technology company, we provide services to help our business customers understand and expand their audiences such as email marketing, lead generation and advertising. As part of those services, we collect certain Personal Data that is then sold as part of our broader service offerings. In almost all cases, only a name, email address, work title and location, and a phone number will be sold. **You can withdraw consent, or otherwise instruct us not to sell, or further sell, your Personal Data at any time by visiting our opt-out/do not sell portal found here.**

### HOW DO WE PROTECT COLLECTED PERSONAL DATA?

#### Our Data Security Program

We have adopted, implemented, and maintain an enterprise-wide corporate data security and privacy program that includes technical, organizational, administrative, and other security measures designed to protect, as required by applicable law, against reasonably anticipated or actual threats to the security of your Personal Data (the **"Security Program"**). We have reason to believe our Security Program is reasonable and appropriate for our business and the nature of foreseeable risks to the Personal Data we collect and process. Nonetheless, we cannot guarantee that your Personal Data, whether during transmission or while stored on our systems, otherwise in our care, or the care of our Vendors, will be free from unauthorized access or that loss or accidental destruction will never occur. Except for our duty under applicable law to maintain the Security Program, we disclaim, to the maximum extent the law allows, any liability for any theft or loss of, unauthorized access or damage to, or interception of any data or communications including Personal Data.

### YOUR GENERAL RIGHTS AND OPTIONS

If we are using your Personal Data to send you marketing materials, such as newsletters or product alerts via email, you may opt out / withdraw your consent by following the instructions linked or otherwise provided in the applicable email or other communication. In addition, residents of certain jurisdictions have additional rights as set forth in the [U.S. State Privacy Rights](#rightsToKnow) and [GDPR Privacy Rights](#exercisingYourRights) sections below. When we receive your request, we will take reasonable steps to remove your name from our distribution lists, but it may take time to do so. You may still receive materials for a period of time after you opt out. Opting out of or changing Affinity Actions or other submissions or requests made on our external social media presence, may require that you do so directly on that applicable platform as we do not control their procedures.

Some information about your use of our Online and Mobile Resources and certain third-party services may be collected using tracking technologies across time and services and used by SMD and third parties for purposes such as to associate different devices you use, and deliver relevant and retargeted ads and/or other content to you on the Service and certain third-party services. Some browsers have a do not track (“DNT”) feature that lets you tell websites that you do not want to have your online activities tracked. We do not support DNT because there is no industry consensus on how they should be treated. We do, however, support Global Privacy Control (“GPC”) in jurisdictions that require it, such as California. The GPC signal communicates a Do Not Sell / Share / Target request from a global privacy control if enabled for that browser or device, or the data subject, if they can be identified. For more information regarding GPC, see the U.S. Privacy Laws section below.

You also have additional rights under certain laws to withdraw consent, limit processing, and/or to instruct us not to sell / share your Personal Data or use it for targeted advertising. We describe those rights and the procedure for exercising them [here](#ComprehensiveLaws).

### CHILDREN'S PRIVACY

U.S. Federal law imposes special restrictions and obligations on commercial website operators who direct their operations toward and collect and use Personal Data from children under the age of 13. Certain Comprehensive Privacy Laws also regulate Personal Data processing practices involving children and other minors. We take those age-related requirements very seriously, and, consistent with them, do not intend for our Online and Mobile Resources to be used by persons under the age of majority, and do not intend to otherwise collect Personal Data from or about minors. Moreover, we do not otherwise knowingly collect Personal Data from minors. If we become aware that anyone under the age of majority has submitted Personal Data to us, we will delete that data other than to retain records of that action. If you are a parent or legal guardian and believe we have collected Personal Data about your minor child, you can contact us [here](#PrivacyOffice). California minors have certain rights in addition to those discussed in this section. Click [here](#CaliforniaMinors) for more information for California minors.

### COMPREHENSIVE PRIVACY LAWS

Privacy and data protection laws vary around the world and among the individual United States. Our obligations arising under the majority of the world’s privacy laws, including U.S. federal and most state laws, are identified by risk assessments that we conduct to ensure we act reasonably and responsibly when processing your Personal Data. In some jurisdictions, however, privacy laws grant you, the data subject, certain specific rights regarding your Personal Data. We refer to these types of privacy laws as **"Comprehensive Privacy Laws."** Examples of Comprehensive Privacy Laws include the European Union (**"EU GDPR"**), and United Kingdom's variant of the General Data Protection Regulation (**"UK GDPR"**) and Switzerland's data protection law based on GDPR (collectively, the **"GDPR"**), and the consumer privacy statutes of several U.S. states, such as California, Colorado, Utah, Virginia, and effective July 1, 2024, Texas (**"U.S. Privacy Laws"**). In other jurisdictions, such as Nevada, more narrow privacy laws have some features of Comprehensive Privacy Laws such as the right to opt-out of the sale of your Personal Data.

The nature and locations of our business activities make us subject to some, though not necessarily all, Comprehensive Privacy Laws. We are for instance, subject to the California Consumer Privacy Act, or **"CCPA"** and the GDPR, and effective July 1, 2024, the Texas Data Privacy and Security Act (**"TDPSA"**). As such, when we collect Personal Data from data subjects protected by the CCPA, TDPSA (once effective), or GDPR, we become subject to, and those data subjects have rights under, those Comprehensive Privacy Laws. This section of our Statement is used to explain your rights under those laws. For purposes of this section, the words **"you** and **"your** mean only California and Texas consumers (as defined by CCPA and TDPSA) and data subjects whose Personal Data was collected while they were in a GDPR jurisdiction.

Questions about how the Comprehensive Privacy Laws of other jurisdictions might apply to us can be directed to us through the contact data found [here](#SDM).

### YOUR RIGHTS AND OUR OBLIGATIONS UNDER U.S. PRIVACY LAWS

#### Categories of Data Collected

We collected and processed the following categories of Personal Data within the 12 months prior to the effective date of this Privacy Statement:

* **identifiers** such as name, address, email address, IP address, and other similar identifiers
* * **Recipients:** Service Providers (e.g., general IT, cloud computing, software, and other business vendors, data analytics providers, data processors, payment processors, and marketing companies), other members of our corporate group, and/or other parties (e.g., litigants and government entities).
    * **Sale/Share:** Third-Party Digital Businesses and our business customers.
* **Personal Data under the Customer Records provision of the California Civil Code** such as a name, address, telephone number, credit card number
* * **Recipients:** Service Providers (e.g., general IT, cloud computing, software, and other business vendors, data processors, and payment processors), other members of our corporate group, and/or other parties (e.g., litigants and government entities).
    * **Sale/Share:** Third-Party Digital Businesses and our business customers.
* **Commercial data** such as products or services purchased or considered
* * **Recipients:** Service Providers (e.g., general IT, cloud computing, software, and other business vendors, data analytics providers, data processors, and marketing companies), other members of our corporate group, and/or other parties (e.g., litigants and government entities).
    * **Sale/Share:** Third-Party Digital Businesses and our business customers.
* **Internet/electronic activity** such as browsing history and search history
* * **Recipients:** Service Providers (e.g., general IT, cloud computing, software, and other business vendors, data analytics providers, data processors, and marketing companies), other members of our corporate group, and/or other parties (e.g., litigants and government entities).
    * **Sale/Share:** Third-Party Digital Businesses and our business customers.
* **Geolocation data** including geographic coordinates/physical location
* * **Recipients:** Service Providers (e.g., general IT, cloud computing, software, and other business vendors, data analytics providers, data processors, and marketing companies), other members of our corporate group, and/or other parties (e.g., litigants and government entities).
    * **Sale/Share:** Third-Party Digital Businesses and our business customers.
* **Audio, video, electronic** or other similar data
* * **Recipients:** Service Providers (e.g., general IT, cloud computing, software, and other business vendors, premises security vendors, and call center providers), other members of our corporate group, and/or other parties (e.g., litigants and government entities).
    * **Sale/Share:** N/A.
* **Professional or employment related data** such as job title and company
* * **Recipients:** Service Providers (e.g., general IT, cloud computing, software, and other business vendors, and data processors), other members of our corporate group, and/or other parties (e.g., litigants and government entities).
    * **Sale/Share:** Our business customers.
* **Inferences drawn from the foregoing** to create a profile about a consumer reflecting the an individual's commercial preferences, predispositions, behavior, and attitudes.
* * **Recipients:** Service Providers (e.g., general IT, cloud computing, software, and other business vendors, data analytics providers, data processors, and marketing companies), other members of our corporate group, and/or other parties (e.g., litigants and government entities).
    * **Sale/Share:** Third-Party Digital Businesses and our business customers.
* **Sensitive Personal Information:** to create a profile about a consumer reflecting the an individual's commercial preferences, predispositions, behavior, and attitudes.
* * **log-in information** (e.g., username and password to online account with Company)
        
    * **Recipients:** Service Providers (e.g., general IT, cloud computing, software, and other business vendors, and data processors), other members of our corporate group, and/or other parties (e.g., litigants and government entities).
    * **Sale/Share:** N/A.

Because there are numerous types of Personal Data in each category, and various uses for each Personal Data type, actual retention periods vary. We retain specific Personal Data pieces based on how long we have a legitimate purpose for the retention. For more information regarding our retention practices, click [here](#HowDataCollect). Generally, we process your Personal Data to provide you services and as otherwise related to the operation of our business, including for one or more of the following business purposes: performing services; managing interactions and transactions; security; debugging; advertising and marketing; quality assurance; processing interactions and transactions; and research and development. We may also use Personal Data for other business purposes in a context that is not a sale or share under applicable U.S. Privacy Laws, such as disclosing it to our service providers, contractors, or processors that perform services for us (“Service Providers”), to you or to other parties at your direction or through your action; for the additional purposes explained at the time of collection (such as in the applicable privacy policy or notice); as required or permitted by applicable law; to the government or private parties to comply with law or legal process or protect or enforce legal rights or obligations or prevent harm; and to assignees as part of an acquisition, merger, asset sale, or other transaction where another party assumes control over all or part of our business (“Additional Business Purposes”). Subject to restrictions and obligations under applicable U.S. Privacy Laws, our Service Providers may also use your Personal Data for Business Purposes and Additional Business Purposes, and may engage subcontractors to enable them to perform services for us.

#### What sources did we obtain Personal Data from and for what reasons did we collect it and do we process it?

Please re-review [this part](#PersonalData) of this Privacy Statement to understand the scope of purposes and the sources from which we collect and for which we process Personal Data.

#### Your U.S. State Privacy Rights

As described more below, subject to meeting the requirements for a Verifiable Consumer Request (defined below) and limitations permitted by applicable U.S. Privacy Law, we provide individuals the privacy rights described in this section, as required by applicable U.S. Privacy Law. Although we have concluded that we are subject only to CCPA and TDPSA (when effective), we will accept requests from consumers under any of the U.S. Privacy Laws, and from residents in states without privacy rights, but will apply our discretion with respect to, and if and how, we process such requests. We will also consider applying state law rights prior to the effective date of such laws, but will do so in our discretion. If you exercise these rights, we will not discriminate against you by treating you differently from other individuals who use our Online and Mobile Resources or purchase our services but did not exercise their rights.

Under CCPA, a consumer includes persons in their capacity as our Workforce and Job Applicants, so accordingly this "Your U.S. State Privacy Rights" section also applies to them. It does not, however, apply to our Workforce or Job Applicants that are not current California residents.

* **Know –** California consumers have the right to request that we disclose to you, specifically beyond the general statement immediately above, the categories of Personal Data collected including the source of the data, our use of it and, if the data was disclosed or sold to third parties, the categories so disclosed or sold as well as the categories of third parties who received or purchased it. This is not applicable in Texas and we reserve the right to limit this to California consumers.
* **Access –** You have the right to receive a copy of the categories and specific elements of Personal Data we collected about you in the preceding 12 months.
* **Correct –** You have the right to request the correction of inaccurate information collected. You can also make changes to your online account in the account settings section of the account. That will not, however, change your information that exists in other places.
* **Delete –** You have the right to request the deletion of Personal Data we collected about you held by us, our Service Providers and any other third party to which we have sold your Personal Data.
* **Opt Out –**You have the right to opt out of any sale, sharing, or targeted advertising of Personal Data (as defined in the CCPA and TDPSA) if such sale / sharing / targeted advertising occurs.
* * Under the CCPA, “share” means to disclose for cross-context behavioral advertising only, and not other forms of disclosure. “Sale” is also broadly defined and does not necessarily need to involve a payment.
    * Due to technical limitations, this opt-out may be exercised separately for cookie and non-cookie data, as explained below.
* **Transfer –**You have the right to request the transfer of specific pieces of Personal Data we have collected about you to another entity.
* **Sensitive Personal Information –**With regard to Personal Data that qualifies as sensitive Personal Data under applicable U.S. Privacy Law, if you elect to provide us with that sensitive Personal Data you will have consented to such processing. We do not process sensitive personal information that is subject to the right to limitation under applicable law. Note, you can terminate your account with us at any time
* **Automated Decision Making / Profiling –** We do not engage in Automated Decision Making or Profiling as defined by U.S. Privacy Laws.

To submit a request to exercise your consumer privacy rights, or to submit a request as an authorized agent, use our [Privacy Rights Request Portal](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/webform/611e70e2-1994-43ff-b07b-646df870db4b/f4165d65-f39c-4ea5-8628-163090b74137) or call us at \[phone number\], and respond to any follow-up inquiries we make. Please be aware that we do not accept or process requests through other means (e.g., via fax, chats, social media etc.). We have the ability to charge a reasonable fee for administrative costs of providing the Personal Data to you in situations where the request is unfounded or excessive (e.g., due to its repeated nature), or in the alternative, we may refuse to act on the request in those situations. We will notify you in such cases

**Opt Out of Sale / Sharing / Targeted Advertising:**

**Opt-out for non-cookie Personal Data:** If you want to limit our processing of your non-cookie Personal Data (e.g., your email address) for targeted advertising, or opt-out of the sale/sharing of such data, make an opt-out request [here](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/webform/611e70e2-1994-43ff-b07b-646df870db4b/f4165d65-f39c-4ea5-8628-163090b74137).

**Opt-out for cookie Personal Data:** If you want to limit our processing of your cookie-related Personal Data for Targeted Advertising, or opt-out of the Sale/Sharing of such Personal Data, some states allow you to exercise a separate opt-out request by clicking the Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information link that can be found for such states in the bottom footer of the site for which you wish to manage cookies. This is because we have to use different technologies to apply your opt-out of cookie Personal Data and to non-cookie Personal Data. Our cookie management tool enables you to exercise such an opt-out request and enable certain cookie preferences on your device. You must exercise your preferences on each of our Online and Mobile Resources you visit, from each browser you use, and on each device that you use. Since your browser opt-out is designated by a cookie, if you clear or block cookies, your preferences will no longer be effective, and you will need to enable them again via our cookie management tool. Beware that if you use ad blocking software, our cookie banner may not appear when you visit our services, and you may have to use the link above (the Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information link at the bottom of our Online and Mobile Resources) to access the tool.

**Out Preference Signals:** You may also opt out of cookie-related sales / sharing / targeted advertising by using an opt-out preference signal or Global Privacy Control (“GPC”). To use a GPC, you can download an internet browser or a plugin to use on your current internet browser and follow the settings to enable the GPC. We have configured the settings of our consent management platform to receive and process GPC signals on our Online and Mobile Resources. If you opt-out using the GPC functionality available in some browsers while you are logged in to one of our Online and Mobile Resources, we will use that signal to opt you out of all online and offline marketing and sharing. If your browser functionality supports GPC but you are not logged into one of our Online and Mobile Resources we will use that signal to opt you out of online tracking only. If your browser does not support GPC you can click on the Your Privacy Choices link at the bottom of our Online and Mobile Resources to activate our cookie manager where you can select your opt out choices for browser activity. If you email or write us with an opt out request, we will use that request to opt you out of all offline based marketing and sharing and any online based marketing and sharing when you are logged into your account in one of our Online and Mobile Resources. We currently do not, due to technical limitations, process GPC for opt-outs of sales and sharing in other contexts (e.g., non-cookie PI) , except if you are logged into one of our online and mobile resources. We do not: (1) charge a fee for use of our service if you have enabled GPC; (2) change your experience with any product or service if you use GPC; or (3) display a notification, pop-up, text, graphic, animation, sound, video, or any interstitial in response to the GP

We do not knowingly sell or share the Personal Data of consumers under 16. If you think we may have unknowingly collected Personal Data of a consumer under 16 years old, please [Contact Us.](#PrivacyOffice) For more information regarding Children's Information, click [here.](#ChildrenPrivacy)

As permitted or required by applicable U.S. Privacy Laws, any request you submit to us must be a Verifiable Consumer Request, meaning when you make a request, we may ask you to provide verifying information, such as your name, e-mail, phone number and/or account information. We will review the information provided and may request additional information (e.g., transaction history) via e-mail or other means to ensure we are interacting with the correct individual. We will not fulfill your Right to Know (Categories), Right to Know (Specific Pieces), Right to Delete, or Right to Correction request unless you have provided sufficient information for us to reasonably verify you are the consumer about whom we collected Personal Data. We do not verify opt-outs of Sell/Share/Target or Limitation of Sensitive Personal Data requests unless we suspect fraud. To protect individuals’ privacy, if we are unable to verify you sufficiently, we will be unable to honor your request. We will verify your access request to a reasonably high level of certainty, meaning that we may match three data points provided by you with data points maintained by us, which we have determined to be reliable for the purpose of verifying you. We verify a California request to know categories to a reasonable degree of certainty, which may include matching at least two data points provided by you with data points maintained by us, which we have determined to be reliable for the purpose of verifying you. If we cannot do so, we will refer you to this Statement for a general description of our data practices. We verify your request to delete to a reasonable degree of certainty, which may include matching at least two reliable data points provided by you with data points maintained by us, or to a reasonably high degree of certainty, which may include matching at least three reliable data points provided by you with data points maintained by us, depending on the sensitivity of the Personal Data and the risk of harm to the consumer posed by unauthorized deletion. If we cannot verify you sufficiently to honor a deletion request, you can still make a do not sell/share/target and/or limit sensitive Personal Data request. We verify your correction request to a reasonable degree of certainty, which may include matching at least two reliable data points provided by you with data points maintained by us, or to a reasonably high degree of certainty, which may include matching at least three reliable data points provided by you with data points maintained by us, depending on the sensitivity of the Personal Data and the risk of harm to the consumer posed by unauthorized correction.

We will use Personal Data provided in a Verifiable Consumer Request only to verify your identity or authority to make the request and to track and document request responses, unless you also gave it to us for another purpose.

You may use an authorized agent to make a request for you, subject to our verification of the agent, the agent’s authority to submit requests on your behalf, and of you. You can learn how to do this by visiting the agent section of our [Consumer Rights Request Portal.](https://privacyportal-cdn.onetrust.com/dsarwebform/611e70e2-1994-43ff-b07b-646df870db4b/c1c0acac-ab24-4dac-b3e6-43421a684626.html) Once your agent’s authority is confirmed, they may exercise rights on your behalf subject to the agency requirements of applicable U.S. Privacy Laws.

You are not required to create a password-protected account with us to make a Verifiable Consumer Request, but you may use your password-protected account to do so. If we suspect fraudulent or malicious activity on or from the password-protected account, we may decline a request or request that you provide further verifying information.

#### Financial Incentives

We do not currently offer discounts or rewards to individuals for providing us Personal Data, or set price or service differences related to the collection, retention, sale, or sharing of Personal Data. If we offer such programs in the future, we will update this Statement to describe such program(s), including how you may opt-in and how we value the Personal Data required.

#### California Minors

Although our services are intended for an audience over the age of majority, any California residents under the age of eighteen (18) who have registered to use our services, and posted content on the service, can request removal by contacting us [here](#PrivacyOffice), detailing where the content is posted and attesting you posted it. We will then make reasonable, good faith efforts to remove the post from prospective public view or anonymize it, so the minor cannot be individually identified to the extent required by applicable law. This removal process cannot ensure complete or comprehensive removal. For instance, third parties may have republished or archived content by search engines we do not control.

#### Shine the Light

We may disclose “personal information,” as defined by California's “Shine the Light” law, to third parties for such third parties own direct marketing purposes. California residents may opt-out of this sharing by contacting us at [\[email protected\]](https://slashdotmedia.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) [\[email protected\]](https://slashdotmedia.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or Slashdot Media, LLC, PO Box 12190, San Diego, CA 92122 (Attn: Privacy Compliance). You must put the statement “Shine the Light Request” in the body of your correspondence. In your request, please attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for your response. This right is different than, and in addition to, CCPA rights, and must be requested separately. However, a Do Not Sell/Share/Target opt-out is broader and will limit our disclosing to third parties for their own direct marketing purposes without the need for making a separate Shine the Light request. We will not accept Shine the Light requests by telephone or by fax, and are not responsible for requests not labeled or sent properly, or that are incomplete.

#### Your Rights and Our Obligations Under Nevada Privacy Law

If you are Nevada resident, Nevada law (SB 220), entitles you to opt out of the sale of certain kinds of Personal Data. A sale under Nevada law is the transfer of Personal Data to third parties for monetary consideration. If you are a Nevada resident and wish to opt-out, you may do so by contacting us at any of the 4 methods [here](#PrivacyOffice) or click on the Opt-Out link at the bottom of our Online and Mobile Resources.

#### Your Rights and Our Obligations under the GDPR

When we collect Personal Data from individuals located in the European Economic Area, Switzerland, or the United Kingdom (the **"GDPR Jurisdictions"**), those individuals have rights under the GDPR. This section of our Statement is used to fulfill our GDPR obligations and explain your GDPR rights. For purposes of this section, the words **"you"** and **"your"** mean only such individuals located in the GDPR Jurisdictions.

#### Our Collection, Use, and Disclosure Practices

Please review [this section](#PersonalData) to understand the scope of purposes and the sources from which we collect Personal Data. Similarly, you can find data about the categories of third parties with which we may disclose your Personal Data and why we disclose it in[this section](#HowLong). We do not use your Personal Data for automated decision-making subject to the right to request human intervention. We do, however, collect certain Personal Data from you for the purpose of selling it subject to having obtained your consent if required under applicable law. We also collect certain Personal Data from third parties. If we are reasonably aware that such third parties have not provided you with appropriate notice of collection by us, we will provide you the required alternate notice under Article 14 of the GDPR when we first contact you using such data or before one month has elapsed, whichever occurs first. We typically provide that Article 14 notice in the body of the communication used to contact you.

#### Legal Basis for Processing Your Personal Data

Our legal basis for collecting and using your Personal Data will depend on the Personal Data concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. However, we will normally collect Personal Data where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms, such as to contact you about products and services you may be interested in. In certain circumstances where our legal basis for processing is for performance of a contract with you, please be aware that, in those circumstances, where you do not provide Personal Data, which is required by us, we will not be able to provide the products and services under our contract with you or your company or may not be able to comply with a legal obligation on us. In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect Personal Data from you or may otherwise need the Personal Data to protect your vital interests or those of another person. If we happen to obtain your consent to process your Personal Data, you may withdraw your consent at any time via any of the means listed [here](#PrivacyOffice). Detailed information regarding the applicable legal basis for processing your Personal Data is provided in this Statement below.

| ### Data voluntarily provided by you when you register on our Online and Mobile Resources, create a free or paid listing, fill out a form, write a review, write a comment, interact with Online and Mobile Resources tools, upload images or content, connect with a Slashdot Media sales representative, correspond with us via e-mail or mail, or subscribe to one of our email lists. This data is directly provided by you. |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Categories of Personal Data we collect voluntarily from you include:**<br><br>* Personal Data such as your full name and contact details such as the name of your company, the state and county in which you are based, your business email address, telephone number, and job title;<br>* Your company website URL;<br>* What you are interested in hearing about (e.g., lead generation or website review);<br>* What advertising channels you use such as pay per click, pay per view, fixed or other advertising channels;<br>* Data about the software you offer (e.g., the product name, type of software and product description);<br>* Data we require so we may invoice you, including your payment details and billing data;<br>* Other data you provide when you communicate with us, including your full name, contact details and business email address, phone number, and details of our communications;<br>* Other information and data you may provide when writing a review, submitting a forum or blog post, submitting a comment, submitting a support or bug ticket, editing a wiki, uploading files or images, open-source code, or inbound emailing to an open-source project list; and<br>* Other data you provide when you communicate with us including your full name, contact details and business email address, phone number and details of any such communications. |     |
| **We use this Personal Data for certain activities, including:** | **We use this Personal Data because:** |
| Fulfilling your requests, for example, to publish your company's listing and other submitted content, to provide your company with details of leads (including their name, data about their business, software requirements and follow up next steps (e.g., request demo)), and to invoice your company appropriately. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Manage and promote our business and brand;<br>* Provide and improve our services;<br>* Operate our business; and<br><br>Obtain payment for our services. |
| Managing your profile and listings. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Provide and improve our services;<br>* Operate our business; and<br>* Improve the performance and user experience of our Online and Mobile Resources.<br><br>We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Provide and improve our services; and<br>* Operate our business. |
| Sending you service emails (e.g., service announcements and messages relating to your account). |
| Providing consultation services. |
| Verifying the validity of your review(s) and ensuring that false, misleading, or malicious reviews are not posted. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to monitor, investigate and prevent any attempts to damage our reputation/ business interests. |
| Sending you email including, but not limited to, service announcements, account related messages, project related updates, and subscribed newsletters. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to manage and promote our business and brand in order to increase our sales.<br><br>You **consented.** You have the right to withdraw this consent by contacting the Data Protection Officer or using the unsubscribe mechanism provided with each communication. |
| Sending marketing information and offers to business contacts regarding SMD services. |
| Notifying you about special offers available from us, our affiliates, or partners, which may be of interest to you. |
| Inviting you to provide reviews about other products and services, and to consider other services provided by SMD. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Manage and promote our business and brand;<br>* Provide and improve our services;<br>* Operate our business; and<br>* Improve the performance and user experience of our Online and Mobile Resources. |
| Providing our services and managing our Online and Mobile Resources (including any compatible processing to otherwise operate our business). | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Manage and promote our business and brand;<br>* Provide and improve our services;<br>* Operate our business; and<br>* Improve the performance and user experience of our Online and Mobile Resources. |
| Responding to your questions, investigating any complaints, and providing customer service. | * We need to process your data to satisfy your requests (**performance of a contract**); or<br>* We have a **legitimate business interest** to resolve any concerns or disputes you may have. |
| Administering our Online and Mobile Resources and our other products and services (including any compatible processing to otherwise operate our business). | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Provide and improve our services; and<br>* Operate our business |
| Customizing your digital experience. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Promote our business and brand;<br>* Improve our services;<br>* Operate our business; and<br>* Improve the performance and user experience of our Online and Mobile Resources. |
| Investigating complaints, providing customer service, and resolving disputes. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Provide and improve our services;<br>* Operate our business;<br>* Monitor, investigate, and report any attempts to breach the security of our Online and Mobile Resources; and<br>* Resolve any concerns or disputes you may have and defend our legitimate interests and protect the company and its shareholders and directors. |
| For internal analytical and research purposes to help us to measure interest in and improve our services | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Manage and promote our business and brand;<br>* Improve our services; and<br>* Improve the performance and user experience of our Online and Mobile Resources. |
| Preventing prohibited or illegal activities. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to monitor, investigate, prevent, and report any attempts to breach the security of our Online and Mobile Resources. |
| Enforcing our policies or terms. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to ensure compliance with the company policies and processes for protecting our business interests and complying with legal obligations. |
| In connection with leads and ads, to disclose it to our business customers and Third-Party Digital Businesses for their own marketing purposes. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to manage and promote our business and brand in order to increase our sales. |
| To comply with any legal requirement or following any mandatory legal process. | **Compliance with a legal obligation.** |

| ### Data we collect about your use of our Online and Mobile Resources (Automatically Collected) |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Categories of Personal Data we collect automatically about you include:**<br><br>* Data recorded in our logs, including URL, IP address, browser and OS data, timestamp, referring site, geolocation, and other standard browser data;<br>* Behavioral data (such as data on the behavior or presumed interests of individuals which are linked to those individuals and may be used to create a user profile) pages viewed, images viewed, documents downloaded, and links to other sites followed; and<br>* Data captured by our cookies (see our [Cookie Policy](https://slashdotmedia.com/opt-out-choices/)). |     |
| **We use this Personal Data for certain activities, including:** | **We use this Personal Data because:** |
| To personalize your experience on our Online and Mobile Resources.<br><br>To operate our Online and Mobile Resources, develop, and improve our products and services for you and for our business customers (including any compatible processing to otherwise operate our business).<br><br>Analytical, statistical and trend analysis to improve the user experience and performance of our Online and Mobile Resources.<br><br>To facilitate your access to and use of our Online and Mobile Resources. | You **consented.** You have the right to withdraw this consent at any time by clicking the Privacy Choices link that can be found in the bottom footer of the site for which you wish to manage cookies. |
| Resolving disputes and troubleshooting problems. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Resolve any concerns or disputes you may have and defend our legitimate interests and protect the company and its shareholders and directors; and<br>* Resolve any issues relating to the Service so that we can comply with our customer contracts. |
| In connection with leads and ads, to disclose it with our business customers and Third Party Digital Businesses for their own marketing purposes. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to manage and promote our business and brand in order to increase our sales.<br><br>* Resolve any concerns or disputes you may have and defend our legitimate interests and protect the company and its shareholders and directors; and<br>* Resolve any issues relating to the Service so that we can comply with our customer contracts. |
| To comply with any legal requirement or following any mandatory legal proces | **Compliance with a legal obligation.** |

| ### Data that we Collect from Other Sources |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Categories of Personal Data we collect about you include:**<br><br>* Contact data, such as name, email address, mailing address and phone number, as well as potentially workplace and job title of the contact persons at prospective customers;<br>* Uniquely identifiable mobile device data;<br>* Geolocation data;<br>* Data collected by third-party tracking technologies, including:<br>    * URL, IP address, browser and OS data, timestamp, referring site, and other standard browser data;<br>    * Behavioral data (such as data on the behavior or presumed interests of individuals which are linked to those individuals and may be used to create a user profile) pages viewed, images viewed, documents downloaded, and links to other sites followed; and<br>    * Behavioral data from interactions with third-party social media sites and applications<br>* Data collected from third-party mail services (as described above). |     |
| **We use this Personal Data for certain activities, including:** | **We use this Personal Data because:** |
| Identifying prospective customers. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to promote our business and brand. |
| Managing customer relationships (including any compatible processing to otherwise operate our business). | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Provide and improve our services; and<br>* Operate our business. |
| Sending you service emails (e.g., service announcements and messages relating to your account). | We have a **legitimate business interest** to manage and promote our business and brand in order to increase our sales.<br><br>* Provide and improve our services;<br>* Operate our business; and<br>* Improve the performance and user experience of our Online and Mobile Resources. |
| Providing consultation services. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to manage and promote our business and brand in order to increase our sales.<br><br>* Provide and improve our services; and<br>* Operate our business. |
| Managing your profile and listings. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to manage and promote our business and brand in order to increase our sales.<br><br>* Provide and improve our services;<br>* Operate our business; and<br>* Improve the performance and user experience of our Online and Mobile Resources. |
| Notifying you about special offers available from us, our affiliates, or partners, which may be of interest to you. | You consented. You have the right to withdraw this consent by contacting the Data Protection Officer or using the unsubscribe mechanism provided with each communication. |
| Sending marketing to business contacts regarding our services and products which may be of interest and to promote our business and brand. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to manage and promote our business and brand. |
| Responding to your questions and requests and otherwise customizing your digital experience. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to:<br><br>* Manage and promote our business and brand;<br>* Provide and improve our services; and<br>* Operate our business. |
| For internal analysis and research to help us to measure interest in and improve our services and other products and services of our customers. |
| Preventing prohibited or illegal activities. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to monitor, investigate, and prevent any attempts to damage our reputation or business interests. |
| Enforcing our policies or terms. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to ensure compliance with company policies and processes for protecting our business interests and complying with legal obligations. |
| In connection with leads and ads, to disclose it with our business customers and Third-Party Digital Businesses for their own marketing purposes. | We have a **legitimate business interest** to manage and promote our business and brand in order to increase our sales. |
| For complying with any legal requirement or following any mandatory legal process. | **Compliance with a legal obligation.** |

#### Your GDPR Privacy Rights

You may exercise the rights available to you under the GDPR, including the [right to object](#ObjectProcessing) to the processing of your Personal Data, as follows:

* **Access –** the right to obtain a confirmation that your Personal Data is being processed, access to your Personal Data (if we are in fact processing it), other data about the processing of your Personal Data (most of which is set forth in this Statement), and a copy of the Personal Data we are processing.
* **Rectification –** the right to have your Personal Data corrected if it is inaccurate, and depending on the purposes of processing, you may also have incomplete Personal Data completed.
* **Erasure –** also known as the “right to be forgotten,” the right to request your Personal Data be deleted under certain circumstances such as if it is no longer needed for the original purpose it was collected for or if you withdraw your consent. The right of erasure does not apply under limited circumstances including if the processing is necessary for exercising the right of freedom of expression and data or our compliance with a legal obligation.
* **Restrict processing –** the right to restrict processing of your Personal Data under certain circumstances such as if you contest the accuracy of the Personal Data (and only for so long as it takes to verify that accuracy), the processing is unlawful and you have requested restriction of the processing rather than erasure, or if we no longer need the Personal Data but you need it to establish, exercise, or defend a legal claim.
* **Portability –** the right to receive the Personal Data you provided to us (and not any other data) under limited circumstances such as if the basis for processing the Personal Data was consent or necessary for the performance of a contract with you, or the processing is carried out by automated means.
* **Automated Processing –** SDM does not engage in automated decision-making activities subject to the right to opt out under the GDPR.
* **Object to processing –** the right to object to the processing of your Personal Data under the following circumstances:
    * Legitimate Interests – if the basis for which the processing occurs is in our legitimate interests or in the performance of a task carried out in the public interest. If you object, we will stop processing your Personal Data unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights, and freedoms or we require the Personal Data to establish, exercise or defend a legal claim.
    * Direct Marketing – if the processing is for direct marketing purposes.

You can exercise these rights by contacting us using the contact data listed [here,](#SDM) however, we may need to request additional data from you to verify your identity before granting your request. We will respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise such rights in accordance with the GDPR. We have the ability to charge a reasonable fee for administrative costs of providing the Personal Data to you in situations where the request is unfounded or excessive (e.g., due to its repeated nature), or in the alternative, we may refuse to act on the request in those situations. We will notify you in such cases.

#### Lodging a Complaint

You have the right to complain to your data protection authority about our collection and use of your Personal Data. Please contact your local data protection authority for more information. Contact data for data protection authorities can be found [here](https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/board/members_en) and [here](https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/).

#### Retaining Your Personal Data

As more fully set forth above, we will store and retain your Personal Data in accordance with applicable law and as long as necessary to carry out the purposes described in this section in accordance with our internal data retention procedures. The criteria used to determine the retention periods include:

* how long the Personal Data is needed in connection with the applicable purposes for which we use it;
* the type of Personal Data collected; and
* whether we are subject to a legal, contractual, or similar obligation to retain the Personal Data (e.g., mandatory data retention laws, government orders to preserve Personal Data relevant to an investigation, or Personal Data that must be retained for the purposes of litigation or disputes).

#### Cross-Border Data Transfer

By submitting Personal Data to us, we will receive it in the United States where our technical infrastructure resides. We undertake such collection solely for the purposes described previously in this Statement but note that such direct collection does not constitute a “transfer” under the GDPR. In certain instances, we collect Personal Data from data subjects located within the GDPR Jurisdictions, and do then transfer it to the U.S., to international organizations, and/or to third countries for the same purposes discussed above. When doing so, may use the mechanisms prescribed for lawful transfers in GDPR Articles 44 through 49, including, where appropriate, then-current standard contractual clauses or similar mechanism appropriate to the particular GDPR Jurisdiction involved. You can request further details in relation to international transfers, including a copy of the standard contractual clauses, by contacting us [here](#SDM).

Notwithstanding anything herein to the contrary, with respect to Personal Data that our business customers transfer to us from the EU, UK, or Switzerland, (i) our Data Privacy Framework Policy applies and provides those data subjects additional rights (you can review our [DPF Policy](https://slashdotmedia.com/dpf-policy/) and learn how to make DPF requests); and/or (ii) to the extent that your Personal Data was transferred to the U.S. pursuant to the standard contractual clauses, such clauses control with respect to our processing of such Personal Data.

### CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT

We reserve the right to change or update this Statement from time to time. Please check our Online and Mobile Resources periodically for such changes since all data collected is subject to the Statement in place at the time of collection. We will indicate the effective/amendment date at the beginning of this Statement.

### HOW TO CONTACT OUR PRIVACY OFFICE

If you have any questions about our privacy and data security policies, procedures, and practices, including anything we say in this Privacy Statement, we encourage you to contact our Privacy Office.

Slashdot Media, LLC

* Address: PO Box 12190 San Diego, CA 92122
* Attn: Privacy Compliance
* Phone: 1-800-552-9000
* Portal: [Slashdot Media Privacy Portal](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/webform/611e70e2-1994-43ff-b07b-646df870db4b/f4165d65-f39c-4ea5-8628-163090b74137)
* Email: [\[email protected\]](https://slashdotmedia.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

### OUR REPRESENTATIVE IN THE EU

_**General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) – European Representative**  
Pursuant to Article 27 of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR),_ **Slashdot Media,  
LLC** _has appointed European Data Protection Office (EDPO) as its GDPR Representative in  
the EU. You can contact EDPO regarding matters pertaining to the GDPR:  
\-by using EDPO’s online request form: [https://edpo.com/gdpr-data-request/](https://edpo.com/gdpr-data-request/)  
\-by writing to EDPO at at Regus Block 1, Blanchardstown Corporate Park, Ballycoolen Road,  
Blanchardstown, Dublin, D15 AKK1, Ireland  
_

### OUR REPRESENTATIVE IN THE UK

_**UK General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) - UK Representative**  
Pursuant to Article 27 of the UK GDPR,_ **Slashdot Media, LLC** _has appointed EDPO UK Ltd  
as its UK GDPR representative in the UK. You can contact EDPO UK regarding matters  
pertaining to the UK GDPR:  
\- by using EDPO’s online request form: [https://edpo.com/uk-gdpr-data-request/](https://edpo.com/uk-gdpr-data-request/)  
\- by writing to EDPO UK at 8 Northumberland Avenue, London WC2N 5BY, United Kingdom_

COMPANY

SOLUTIONS

POLICIES & TERMS

[

Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information](https://slashdotmedia.com/opt-out-modal)

QUICK LINKS

FOLLOW

[

](https://www.facebook.com/SlashdotMedia/)[

](https://twitter.com/SlashdotMedia)[

](https://www.linkedin.com/company/slashdot-media/)

Copyright © 2024 Slashdot Media, LLC
